<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on TRIZ Innovation India</title>
    <link>http://trizindia.org/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on TRIZ Innovation India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 02:26:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://trizindia.org/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TrizTrends 2014</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/triztrends-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 02:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/triztrends-2014/</guid>
      <description>Set in the picturesque GE Bangalore campus had some interesting pick of speakers. Thanks to GE for being a great host.
Peter from Reliance was hyper selective with his picks with just the contradiction and principles as the approach and I liked what worked in teams from his experiments.
Of course he hit the mark with India being a country of contradictions.
Sergei shared some interesting roi numbers and gave clear idea of Triz evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CALL FOR PAPERS – TRIZ FUTURE CONFERENCE 2014</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/call-for-papers-triz-future-conference-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 09:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/call-for-papers-triz-future-conference-2014/</guid>
      <description>European TRIZ Association (ETRIA) is organizing TRIZ Future Conference (TFC2014) along with Exelop SA will be hosted by EPFL Lausanne, Switzerland. TFC2014 is also sponsored by CIRP, the international Academy for Production Engineering. TFC2014 will provide an international forum for exchanging new ideas on knowledge‐ based innovation and TRIZ, presenting recent achievements by the scientific community and enabling further advances and collaboration also with the industrial community.      CALL FOR PAPERS   TRIZ FUTURE CONFERENCE 14   Global innovation Convention   &amp;nbsp;  &amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;page_2&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt; Place: &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; EPFL (Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne), Switzerland &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt; Duration: &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; From 29th to 31th October 2014 &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt; Cost: &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; 650 EUR per participant (Further prices for students, Early birds, others are available on www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Trends 2014, A Conference in GE India</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/02/triz-trends-2014-a-conference-in-ge-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 12:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/02/triz-trends-2014-a-conference-in-ge-india/</guid>
      <description>(Image courtesy: http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/)     TRIZ Trends 2014        (Image courtesy: http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/)     TRIZ Trends 2014    
(Image courtesy: http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/) John F. Welch Technology Center, Bangalore, INDIA is hosting an event on
Time: Thursday &amp;#8211; March 20, 2014 
Venue: John F. Welch Technology Center, Bangalore, INDIA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Developers Summit-2011</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2011/02/triz-developers-summit-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2011/02/triz-developers-summit-2011/</guid>
      <description>http://www.triz-summit.ru/en/section.php?docId=4908
Information Letter 1   Information letter #1, November 30, 2010.     TRIZ Summit 2011      Dear colleagues!   1. The Organizing Committee of TRIZ Developers Summit selected the topic for Summit-2011 &amp;#8211; it is &amp;#8220;Action Principle of Systems&amp;#8221;. This topic is very important for TRIZ research. It embraces issues of system modeling, functional analysis and synthesis, trends of engineering systems evolution and methods for forecasting via transfer of functions and trends of such systems, and terminology issues in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: TrizIn 2011 – 2nd Annual TRIZ India Summit</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2011/01/call-for-papers-trizin-2011-2nd-annual-triz-india-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 19:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2011/01/call-for-papers-trizin-2011-2nd-annual-triz-india-summit/</guid>
      <description>This is a Call for Papers to be presented at the 2nd Annual TRIZ India Summit, taking place on July 28 &amp;amp; 29, 2011 at Bangalore. The summit is being organized by Crafitti Consulting in partnership with The Altshuller Institute for TRIZ Studies (AITRIZ).
http://2011.trizindiasummit.com
 Summit Topics  TRIZ Papers  Our emphasis is on REAL case studies of TRIZ being applied in problem solving and innovation contexts. We are strongly interested in providing content for corporate and academic use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ India Summit 2010 proceedings are now online!</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2010/11/triz-india-summit-2010-proceedings-are-now-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2010/11/triz-india-summit-2010-proceedings-are-now-online/</guid>
      <description>Crafitti is pleased to announce that TRIZ India Summit 2010 proceedings are now public and online! You can access the proceedings at https://sites.google.com/a/crafitti.com/triz-india-summit-2010/. Please feel free to share the link with your network.      In lieu of our strategic partnership with Altshuller Institute for TRIZ Studies, TRIZ India Summit 2010 papers are also part of TRIZCON 2010 proceedings! You can access TRIZCON 2010 proceedings at http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling the Innovation Summit – Surviving the Avalanches and Avoidng the Yetis – Growing Ideas into Innovation</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2010/11/scaling-the-innovation-summit-surviving-the-avalanches-and-avoidng-the-yetis-growing-ideas-into-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 13:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2010/11/scaling-the-innovation-summit-surviving-the-avalanches-and-avoidng-the-yetis-growing-ideas-into-innovation/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to address the CII Karnataka Innovation Forum last week. I spoke about the Challenges in growing ideas into innovation. I outlined the Innovation FlowTM Framework and gave a quick intro to TRIZ-based Innovative Problem Solving. There was good interest from the Innovation forum to learn more about TRIZ.. I plan to do a one-day innovation workout for them next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two TRIZ India Summit 2010 Papers featured on AITRIZ this month!</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2010/09/two-triz-india-summit-2010-papers-featured-on-aitriz-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2010/09/two-triz-india-summit-2010-papers-featured-on-aitriz-this-month/</guid>
      <description>Two TRIZ India Summit 2010 papers are featured on this month&amp;#8217;s AITRIZ edition of Inside TRIZ, as a follow-up of Crafitti&amp;#8217;s strategic partnership with AI for TRIZ India Summit.
       Enhancing Air Safety for Pilots and ATC using TRIZ, A.K.Dhamija, K. Ramachandran, Divya Gautam, DRDO http://www.aitriz.org/articles/InsideTRIZ/323031303039695452495A.pdf   Determining Qualitative Parameters Using TRIZ for Estimating IP Value of Intangibles, Pinaki Ghosh, Subhadip Sarkar, Prasanna C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Updates TRIZIN 2010 Bangalore</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2010/07/live-updates-trizin-2010-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2010/07/live-updates-trizin-2010-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>Starting the day with explaining contradictions of Ganesha to Ellen and Isak
Watch comments of this post for more live updates</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International IPR Conference @ Bangalore</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/international-ipr-conference-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 03:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/international-ipr-conference-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>ITAG is organizing a conference on IP Leveraging in Software, Electronics and Green Technology in co-operation with Sughrue Mion PLLC, a leading law firm in USA and Bangalore Chamber of Industry and Commerce as our co organizer.. The conference will be held on 29th -30th January 2010 at Hotel LaLiT Ashok, Bangalore. The main objective of this conference is to create IP awareness in the field of Software, Electronics Industry and in Green Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Clinic at MindTree</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/triz-clinic-at-mindtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 12:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/triz-clinic-at-mindtree/</guid>
      <description>Wow!! quite some time since I caught up with TRIZ India. Lot of things going on in MindTree on the TRIZ front. Murali (also a TRIZ India member) and I came up with the concept of TRIZ Clinic.
The Metaphor
Basically, we added the metaphor of a clinic to the problem definition and solution. Picture this &amp;#8211; a patient would go to a doc for a checkup when they have a fever or a cough or one such ailment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>