<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wonderland on TRIZ Innovation India</title>
    <link>http://trizindia.org/tags/wonderland/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wonderland on TRIZ Innovation India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://trizindia.org/tags/wonderland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventor in Wonderland</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2011/12/inventor-in-wonderland-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2011 03:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2011/12/inventor-in-wonderland-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRIZ podcast series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Become a member at TRIZIndia.org for FREE to connect with the world&amp;#8217;s experts on inventive problem solving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/w/?v=l9d0398v4yY&#34;&gt;http://youtube.com/w/?v=l9d0398v4yY&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala Ramadurai, Innovation Facilitator, MindTree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar Venugopal, Innovation Leader, Honeywell, emerging markets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali Loganathan, 4 years TRIZ practitioner, across industries in MindTree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcast series in TRIZ tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the 1st podcast on Ideal Final Result&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Father of TRIZ &amp;#8211; Altshuller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;value addition linked to Ideal Final Result (IFR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is your experience with IFR?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar says &amp;#8211; Challenge &amp;#8211; mode of thinking into ideality &amp;#8211; common way of thinking is on constraints &amp;#8211; ideality is implementation free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali says &amp;#8211; break psychological inertia (PI) &amp;#8211; PI comes in the way of ideation. Think backwards in time &amp;#8211; put constraints in the back. Vision and mission brings grandiose picture. Thinking backward in time, one cannot lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala quotes Murali &amp;#8211; cannot lie backward in time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freeland &amp;#8211; no harm, only benefits &amp;#8211; Wonderland with only benefits &amp;#8211; problem already solved. Psychologists have proved that lying is difficult backward in time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; SCAMPER &amp;#8211; M &amp;#8211; maximize/minimize&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 steps &amp;#8211; what should be maximized or minimized? zero cost &amp;#8211; barrier to thinking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; Isak Burkhman &amp;#8211; nothing ideal or final about IFR. Free, perfect, now &amp;#8211; ideal definition for IFR. Use metaphors &amp;#8211; Wonderland is a better metaphor than IFR. Result = Process = goes forward in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heaven or Wonderland &amp;#8211; popular interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; Example &amp;#8211; Altshuller &amp;#8211; coolant leakage &amp;#8211; usual way is trial and error. What if coolant is Cindrella? Cindrella shouts out &amp;ldquo;Here I am&amp;rdquo;. How do you make Cindrella is visible? Turn off the lights. Then solution &amp;#8211; Coolant needs to be colour emitting and says &amp;ldquo;Hi, I am here&amp;rdquo;. Ideal coolant or ideal way to leak? 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; Free transport &amp;#8211; A to B? marketing campaigns lets you go from A to B for a cause &amp;#8211; global warming, travelogue writing &amp;#8211; have fun for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; Why fly? find out the reason for flying. IFR + 5 whys gives a stronger solution. Fundamental problem identified and can arrive at solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; CISCO cashed in on financial meltdown when corporates were slashing down prices &amp;#8211; different domain, different solution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/w/?v=GU0w0B2LNEE&#34;&gt;http://youtube.com/w/?v=GU0w0B2LNEE&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternate use of IFR &amp;#8211; visioning. What should my team be doing in 2014, say? who are my customers? what is their IFR? work your way backwards and write down what your team should be doing now to meet that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; customer, customer&amp;#8217;s customer, supplier &amp;#8211; all of their IFRs are different. There could be conflicts or contradictions in each others&amp;#8217; IFR. How does one solve this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; No compromise. AND is essential. customer wins AND Supplier wins. Inventive principles can help out here. First figure out IFR for all parties and solve the clash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar adds &amp;#8211; clashes are going to be standard practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; IFR + 9-windows can be combined. 9-windows spread in time and space. Mouse &amp;#8211; system, stuff around it &amp;#8211; phone, laptop, screen &amp;#8211; supersystem. Subsystem &amp;#8211; hardware wheel, software, components. All these things back in time and forward in time, what were they? You have 9-windows. System evolves from trackpad, mouse, touchscreen &amp;#8211; moves towards to an IFR. All systems/components move toward IFR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali comments on Worst Final Result (WFR) &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heaven: IFR = Hell: WFR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You find out where systems can go wrong and fix it before things go drastically wrong&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; take a pen and design a non-working pen and reverse to get a good pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; IFR in groups &amp;#8211; difficult to think of completely ideal future without accidents or lucky breaks (events). Publishing industry &amp;#8211; internet was an accident for publishing. IFR needs an accident or break. electricity and other fundamental innovations can change course of other innovation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; Accident can be looked at as an enabler. Author &amp;#8211; IFR &amp;#8211; should be able to write a book and reach the audience instantly. Reader &amp;#8211; read and access books instantly. Internet came in and enabled this. IFR can really help and accidents can be handled or enabled&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; Luckily, internet happened. George Lucas, starwars, was way ahead of his time in terms of graphics. Graphics and sound effects in the &amp;#8217;70s sucked. He later remastered the Starwars series when technology was available&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; do IFR for everyday objects around yourself before jumping to applying to your tech problems. Make yourself at ease&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; Add &amp;ldquo;Self&amp;rdquo; as a prefix to make anything ideal. That is the way to get an IFR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; take something that you care about and apply IFR for permanent change&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next time on TRIZ podcast series from TRIZIndia.org&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>