<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TRIZ Innovation India</title>
    <link>http://trizindia.org/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TRIZ Innovation India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 10:03:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://trizindia.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ India Podcast with Jack Hipple – Interesting Case of the Hairnet bags and the Lucy Show</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2016/01/triz-india-podcast-with-jack-hipple-hairnet-bags-and-the-lucy-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 10:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2016/01/triz-india-podcast-with-jack-hipple-hairnet-bags-and-the-lucy-show/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;width: 298px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.idsa.org/sites/default/files/colleenb/Jack%20Hipple%20Photo_cb_0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;288&#34; height=&#34;288&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Jack Hipple
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bala Ramadurai, Co-founder of TRIZ Innovation India (trizindia.org) has a chat with Jack Hipple, Chemical Engineer, TRIZ practitioner and trainer (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.innovation-triz.com/personnel/JHipple.html&#34;&gt;http://www.innovation-triz.com/personnel/JHipple.html&lt;/a&gt;) about his experiences on learning and applying TRIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the podcast from here &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/download/JackHippleTRIZIndiapodcast/JackHipple-TRIZIndiapodcast.mp3&#34;&gt;https://archive.org/download/JackHippleTRIZIndiapodcast/JackHipple-TRIZIndiapodcast.mp3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. When did you come across TRIZ? When did you decide to take on TRIZ as your path forward in your career?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An accident. As Director of Dow Chemical&amp;#8217;s Discovery Research program, an attempt to broaden Dow&amp;#8217;s business beyond commodity chemicals, I sought out training in many psychologically based creativity tools such as brainstorming, CPS, Debono&amp;#8217;s Lateral Thinking and Six Hats. I found these tools rather unproductive and time consuming when it came to serious technical problems. After my 26 years with Dow in 1993, I became a project manager for the National Center for Manufacturing Sciences, and as part of this role, decided to gain some knowledge of quality tools and attended a quality conference in Detroit, MI in 1994 when I learned a little about QFD, the house of quality, measurement tools, and around 3:30 in the afternoon, when I was thinking about leaving, I looked at the agenda and saw a talk by two Russian scientists (and I have apologized many times for not remembering their names) entitled &amp;#8220;The Use of TRIZ to resolve the contradiction of Pizza Box Design&amp;#8221;. First of all, I had no idea what &amp;#8220;TRIZ&amp;#8221; was nor what cosmic issues were involved in the design of pizza boxes. So I stayed out of total curiosity, and as we all have had at one time or another, it was a life changing event. The talk was about a very practical aspect of take out pizza. You want the pizza to be hot, but when it is, it gives off steam which softens the cardboard lid, causing it to sag into the pizza and when you lift the lid at home, it takes a good deal of the pizza topping with it. So there&amp;#8217;s a contradiction (and everyone involved in TRIZ knows that solving a contradiction is the key to an invention). The little plastic tripod found in most all take out pizzas (at least in the US) was invented with TRIZ. It resolves this contradiction in a very simple way. I literally fell off my chair after hearing this presentation and resolved to learn some more about this process. It took a couple of years for me to pursue TRIZ with any significant time, but it became my primary career in 2001 after serving in project manager roles at the National Center for Manufacturing Sciences and Cabot Corporation, neither of which allowed me to use TRIZ in any significant way. I was hired by one of the TRIZ software companies and became their primary chemical industry trainers for TRIZ and later by a management consulting company interested in bringing TRIZ into their business. I started my own company in 2001 and also began dong TRIZ training for the American Society of Mechanical Engineers and the American Institute of Chemical Engineers in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. What were some of the challenges that you faced on the way? How did you overcome it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think anyone who has started their own business has had to overcome the short term lack of cash flow and the slow process of reintroducing your self to prior contacts and telling them you had something new they might be interested in. There were also presentation at appropriate conferences trying to get the word out. It also helps to have a very supportive family. Though we had become empty nesters by the time my business got started, my wife went back to work to help sustain us and also provide medical insurance coverage, which always more expensive when it is bought privately and not through a group policy. Without this support, it would have been difficult to get things off the ground. The challenge in getting the professional engineering societies interested took a while to overcome, but once done, provided both income and possible client contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3. What are some of the common learning difficulties that one should avoid while learning and applying TRIZ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two primary difficulties in starting with TRIZ within an organization. The first is ego. The primary postulate within TRIZ is that there a limited number of inventive principles that we continuously reuse. This is not typically recognized within an industry or company due, in part, to the extensive use of acronyms and fancy words that make someone think that there problem is special and unique. It almost never is. One of the exercises I run with my clients or within a workshop is to force the attendees to describe their problem to a ten year old. The language is never the same and using these much simpler, more generic terms in a Google search will yield at least an order of magnitude more possible areas to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second barrier is not being willing to take the time to sufficiently define what the problem is that we are attempting to solve. It is always amazing to me, as an outsider working with a client (and I am told the team has been working on some problem for a long time), and using any one of a number of TRIZ problem definition tools, that these groups, when separated, come back with very different definitions of the problem. The good or bad functions are not seen the same, the number of contradiction is not the same, etc. They have spent a huge amount of time trying to solve the wrong problem. Though this is one of TRIZ&amp;#8217;s greatest strengths, it is also a very time consuming step. There are many organizations I have worked with that simply can&amp;#8217;t or won&amp;#8217;t take this time and TRIZ implementation is a failure. As frustrating as this is, I have learned to accept this fact and it is one shared by many other TRIZ professionals that I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4. The common belief about TRIZ that I hear a lot is that TRIZ is only for engineers. I am sure you&amp;#8217;ve heard that a lot as well. What are some of your experiences that should tell the listeners of this podcast otherwise?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though much of my work is in the technical area, the principals of TRIZ can be equally well applied in what I call &amp;#8220;soft&amp;#8221; applications. There are contradictions and functional conflicts in marketing, business strategy, and human resources. I find the use of the basic TRIZ separation principles particularly useful in these situations. The problems in this area are easier to define, but as opposed to the technical area, may have even more views of what is &amp;#8220;ideal&amp;#8221;, what &amp;#8220;resources&amp;#8221; are available, and what the important contradictions are that need to be resolved. It is also important for TRIZ professionals to not overstate what TRIZ can accomplish in this area. For example, TRIZ is not the right tool to help decide what the color of something should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some technical areas that TRIZ has some limited applications such as pure chemical synthesis and biological processes. Though there some interesting examples that we can point to, there is not, in my opinion anything close to a contradiction table or AREIZ algorithm for either of these areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;5. In your experience, what is an excellent example of application of TRIZ that still stands out?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one in particular which is no longer covered by a confidentiality agreement and that is one of my first major commercial projects with S.C. Johnson, a multi-billion $$, privately held, consumer products company that manufactures a multitude of cleaning and household products. When Dow decided to divest itself of its consumer products business (products such as Dow Oven Cleaner, Handiwrap, Saran Wrap, Bathroom cleaner) it sold this business to S.C. Johnson, already a major player in this business space. After this business sale, Dow continued to sell the Saran polymer to S.C. Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are unaware that this plastic wrap is not the same polymer/plastic as others, which are primarily polyethylene. This plastic has excellent barrier to moisture transfer, but very poor barrier against oxygen transfer. Saran is a copolymer of vinyl chloride and vinylidene chloride and has outstanding barrier properties to both and this is important in the preservation of many fruits and vegetables. Unfortunately, along with this plus, the negative is that this polymer has very poor tensile strength, and in its typical roll form, splits and tears and since it is clear, the consumer cannot readily find where the film cut was and in many cases would simply throw away the product and return to using polyethylene, knowing that it is not as good a product. So the polymer itself was superior, but its form was not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When S.C. Johnson inherited this product from Dow, and with its far greater sensitivity to consumer needs, decided to change the form of the product into something that looked liked a &amp;#8220;hairnet bag&amp;#8221; which would stretch around any size container and eliminate the need to a roll form and its limitations. That&amp;#8217;s where the great idea stopped being so great. The decision was made to ship the plastic film overseas where it would be converted into its hairnet shape and then &amp;#8220;wrap&amp;#8221; ten of these bags with a double rubber band wrap (think about how much fun this was for a plant operator to do), and then ship back thousands of these bundles, compressed in an overseas shipping container (don&amp;#8217;t want to pay for space not used!), back to Racine, WI (S.C. Johnson&amp;#8217;s primary corporate site), where another operator would now have to do two very difficult tasks. First, take the rubber band off (not easy and ergonomic injuries are possible), and while this is being done, try to grab the bags, which now want to fly everywhere, and stuff them In a cottage container and put a lid on it. Those on this podcast from the US may remember the famous Lucy TV show where the bakery line was slowly sped up and Lucy had to keep up and that&amp;#8217;s exactly what this looked like. (Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HnbNcQlzV-4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HnbNcQlzV-4&lt;/a&gt; for the snippet)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short introduction to TRIZ principles, the project team quickly came up with a simple solution which allowed the entire process to be simplified with huge cost savings and that was to simply put nine bags into the tenth bag. No rubber bands, virtually no labor (process could be automated), the packing simplified, the shelf space reduced dramatically (just hang on a spindle) and since there was no human involvement, sterilization costs were virtually eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I frequently use this example in my workshops as it illustrates the use of the simplest of TRIZ tools (IFR: the bags package themselves, RESOURCES: use an existing bag instead of a rubber band, and TRIMMING: get rid of the band and additional packaging)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6. What is you advice to the listeners of this podcast who want to start off applying TRIZ? If you have worked with Indian companies, please give us some Indian context as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not had the pleasure of working with any Indian companies, but my advice to anyone starting out with TRIZ is to NEVER start with any software product. It is critical to get the brain part down first; the basic TRIZ algorithm, the use of the IFR, resources, and contradictions. Once these are well understood, software can be considered, but I am constantly amazed at how many problems are solved with the simplest of TRIZ tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;7. Hypothetical question to end this podcast &amp;#8211; According to you, what developments in the invention world would Altshuller have commented, &amp;#8220;Wish I had thought of that!&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure if Altshuller recognized or saw the degree to which TRIZ could be applied in business, strategic, IP, and organizational problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some References suggested by Jack Hipple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His books are given below: If anyone is interested in bulk discounts of these books, please let us know and we&amp;#8217;ll be happy to pass it on to Jack Hipple (admin AT trizindia DOT org)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aitriz.org/online-store/triz-online-store/books/ideal-result-detail&#34;&gt;http://www.aitriz.org/online-store/triz-online-store/books/ideal-result-detail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springer.com/us/book/9781461437062&#34;&gt;http://www.springer.com/us/book/9781461437062&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chemical Engineering Progress series is at;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiche.org/resources/publications/cep/2005/april/solve-problems-inventively&#34;&gt;http://www.aiche.org/resources/publications/cep/2005/april/solve-problems-inventively&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiche.org/resources/publications/cep/2005/may/use-triz-reverse-analyze-failures&#34;&gt;http://www.aiche.org/resources/publications/cep/2005/may/use-triz-reverse-analyze-failures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aiche.org/resources/publications/cep/2005/june/use-triz-plan-forecast-and-think-strategically&#34;&gt;http://www.aiche.org/resources/publications/cep/2005/june/use-triz-plan-forecast-and-think-strategically&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go to these CEP pages, you will see, at the bottom, a link and info about reprints, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is an AIChE member can download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His next public TRIZ classes for ASME are in Las Vegas and Atlanta:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.asme.org/products/courses/triz&amp;amp;#8211;the-theory-of-inventive-problem-solving&#34;&gt;https://www.asme.org/products/courses/triz&amp;amp;#8211;the-theory-of-inventive-problem-solving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His other podcasts are available at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ideaconnection.com/open-innovation-articles/&#34;&gt;http://www.ideaconnection.com/open-innovation-articles/&lt;/a&gt; (scroll down a bit)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as well as for Georgia Tech:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://smartech.gatech.edu/handle/1853/48282&#34;&gt;https://smartech.gatech.edu/handle/1853/48282&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Vladimir Petrov, a TRIZ Master</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2015/10/interview-with-vladimir-petrov-a-triz-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 09:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2015/10/interview-with-vladimir-petrov-a-triz-master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/bala-photo1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-358&#34; src=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/bala-photo1.png&#34; alt=&#34;bala-photo1&#34; width=&#34;144&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Vladimir-Petrov.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-353&#34; src=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Vladimir-Petrov-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vladimir-Petrov&#34; width=&#34;155&#34; height=&#34;155&#34; srcset=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Vladimir-Petrov-300x300.jpg 300w, http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Vladimir-Petrov.jpg 370w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 155px) 100vw, 155px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vladimir Petrov (Profile here &amp;#8211; ) has been an avid supporter of TRIZ Innovation India and has always volunteered to spread awareness of TRIZ in India, which is the mission of TRIZ Innovation India. His simple reply to my email was &amp;#8220;How can I help TRIZ India?&amp;#8221;. I present excerpts from our online interview, which was the result of his offer of help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bala Ramadurai: From your track record, you have not only taught TRIZ, but also practically used it, as is obvious from your publications and patents. How did you get started with TRIZ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vladimir Petrov&lt;/strong&gt;: I started studying TRIZ by correspondence with Altshuller in 1972. He led the two-year university program and I successfully completed the program. At the time, I was an R&amp;amp;D engineer. I immediately began to apply TRIZ in my work and also helped others solve their problems. In parallel, I passed TRIZ knowledge to my staff as well. In 1973, I started my teaching experience in TRIZ to my first group of 25 persons, a 120 hour program. That was my beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BR&lt;/strong&gt;: Please describe some of your memorable experiences with Altshuller. How was he as a teacher, friend?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP&lt;/strong&gt;: About Altshuller, I have a lot of memories. This alone, I could write a great book. He was my teacher and colleague. We not only taught together at various occasions, we discussed various aspects of TRIZ as well. He became a friend of mine. When he came to Leningrad, he lived in my house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BR&lt;/strong&gt;: You have travelled across the globe teaching TRIZ. What according to you are some conditions that need to be there in place for TRIZ to be learnt and applied?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP&lt;/strong&gt;: In my opinion, the most important thing is that people have to have a desire to learn TRIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BR&lt;/strong&gt;: Some people often question if TRIZ is meant only for engineers and technologists. What will be your response to such a question?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP&lt;/strong&gt;: TRIZ methodology is universal and can be applied to any field of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BR&lt;/strong&gt;: Are there problems that TRIZ should not be used for solving? if so, which ones are those fields?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP&lt;/strong&gt;: TRIZ cannot be applied effectively when one does not have enough knowledge or experience with a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BR&lt;/strong&gt;: Are there some problems that you solved or helped solve only to realize that the market for application of the solution had moved on and the solution was not relevant any more?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP&lt;/strong&gt;: Even in this case, the specialist will solve problems faster and better than a non specialist only if they apply inventive thinking skills (TRIZ thinking).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BR&lt;/strong&gt;: Please tell us about your latest book. How will it benefit our readers on TRIZ India?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP&lt;/strong&gt;: My latest book is written in Russian. It still needs to be translated into English. It&amp;#8217;s a big job and I&amp;#8217;m looking for helpers and sponsors. Maybe someone from your association can help me. This is a TRIZ tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BR&lt;/strong&gt;: Last question, what should practitioners from India do differently when applying TRIZ to solve problems?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VP&lt;/strong&gt;: Unfortunately, I do not know how and what you are doing [in India] now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Glossary Book</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2015/09/triz-glossary-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 07:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2015/09/triz-glossary-book/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;img-class-aligncenter-src-https-gallery-mailchimp-com-a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab-images-3137fb77-1256-4fe9-ba81-63a440ef31f2-png-alt-width-181-height-286-align-none-data-cke-saved-src-https-gallery-mailchimp-com-a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab-images-3137fb77-1256-4fe9-ba81-63a440ef31f2-png-null&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; aligncenter&#34; src=&#34;https://gallery.mailchimp.com/a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab/images/3137fb77-1256-4fe9-ba81-63a440ef31f2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;181&#34; height=&#34;286&#34; align=&#34;none&#34; data-cke-saved-src=&#34;https://gallery.mailchimp.com/a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab/images/3137fb77-1256-4fe9-ba81-63a440ef31f2.png&#34; /&gt; {.null}&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRIZ Glossary book written by Prof. Vladimir Petrov is now available at an introductory price of USD 0.99 in the link given below. Prof. Petrov&amp;#8217;s linkedin profile is here &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;https://il.linkedin.com/pub/vladimir-petrov-triz/6/30a/700&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; data-cke-saved-href=&#34;https://il.linkedin.com/pub/vladimir-petrov-triz/6/30a/700&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://il.linkedin.com/pub/vladimir-petrov-triz/6/30a/700&#34;&gt;https://il.linkedin.com/pub/vladimir-petrov-triz/6/30a/700&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to the book is given here &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.in/TRIZ-Glossary-Vladimir-Petrov-ebook/dp/B013YE59M2/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1441695997&amp;sr=1-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; data-cke-saved-href=&#34;http://www.amazon.in/TRIZ-Glossary-Vladimir-Petrov-ebook/dp/B013YE59M2/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1441695997&amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.in/TRIZ-Glossary-Vladimir-Petrov-ebook/dp/B013YE59M2/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1441695997&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;http://www.amazon.in/TRIZ-Glossary-Vladimir-Petrov-ebook/dp/B013YE59M2/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1441695997&amp;amp;sr=1-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ India Podcast – TRIZ Journal – Part 1</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2015/09/triz-india-podcast-triz-journal-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 07:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2015/09/triz-india-podcast-triz-journal-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gallery.mailchimp.com/a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab/images/83727d47-c365-469f-90d0-a37e8bd1c3d7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;148&#34; height=&#34;164&#34; align=&#34;none&#34; data-cke-saved-src=&#34;https://gallery.mailchimp.com/a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab/images/83727d47-c365-469f-90d0-a37e8bd1c3d7.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gallery.mailchimp.com/a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab/images/c4b447c3-58a9-4af5-a5a2-9b8fdb7b409f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;115&#34; height=&#34;164&#34; align=&#34;none&#34; data-cke-saved-src=&#34;https://gallery.mailchimp.com/a4fe36e0021432bc3bc87a8ab/images/c4b447c3-58a9-4af5-a5a2-9b8fdb7b409f.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bala Ramadurai, Co-founder of TRIZ Innovation India (trizindia.org) has a chat with Dr. Ellen Domb, co-founder of PQR group and co-founding editor of TRIZ Journal, in a 2 part series of podcasts on TRIZ Journal 2.0 or better still, TRIZ Journal 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of the series will involve a conversation with current TRIZ Journal Editors &amp;#8211; Dr. Phil Samuel and Derek Bennington&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; data-cke-saved-href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1&#34;&gt;https://archive.org/details/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the offline version from &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/download/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1/TRIZIndiaPodcast-TRIZ-Journal-1.mp3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; data-cke-saved-href=&#34;https://archive.org/download/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1/TRIZIndiaPodcast-TRIZ-Journal-1.mp3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/download/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1/TRIZIndiaPodcast-TRIZ-Journal-1.mp3&#34;&gt;https://archive.org/download/TRIZIndiaPodcastTRIZJournalPart1/TRIZIndiaPodcast-TRIZ-Journal-1.mp3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Forecasting – A Primer</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/06/technology-forecasting-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 09:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/06/technology-forecasting-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I promised a &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/2014/02/the-history-of-triz/&#34; title=&#34;The history of TRIZ&#34;&gt;while ago&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;#8217;d publish something about Technology Forecasting, which is my current occupation in Milan, Italy. I presented a talk on technology forecasting in Politecnico di Milano. I have attached the slideshow to this post. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to download the presentation [google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/uc?id=0B3EZPxN_ojAfTV9aazdCRWx1Rms&amp;amp;export=download&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/uc?id=0B3EZPxN_ojAfTV9aazdCRWx1Rms&amp;amp;export=download&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; title=&amp;#8221;2013_03_08_Bala_Ramadurai-Technology Forecasting.pptx&amp;#8221; icon=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_10_powerpoint_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_10_powerpoint_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; style=&amp;#8221;download&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fsSr-IG9tO99z5Zb0eht2nTwcWtvfnOaJjsZVfl2hvI/preview&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fsSr-IG9tO99z5Zb0eht2nTwcWtvfnOaJjsZVfl2hvI/preview&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; title=&amp;#8221;2013_03_08_Bala_Ramadurai-Technology Forecasting&amp;#8221; icon=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; width=&amp;#8221;100%&amp;#8221; height=&amp;#8221;400&amp;#8243; style=&amp;#8221;embed&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract from ARIZ 71 – The Algorithm of Problem Solving</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/05/ariz-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 11:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/05/ariz-71/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/preview&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/preview&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; title=&amp;#8221;ARIZ-71&amp;#8243; icon=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; width=&amp;#8221;100%&amp;#8221; height=&amp;#8221;400&amp;#8243; extra=&amp;#8221;undefined&amp;#8221; style=&amp;#8221;embed&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/edit?usp=drivesdk&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/edit?usp=drivesdk&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; title=&amp;#8221;ARIZ-71&amp;#8243; icon=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; newwindow=&amp;#8221;yes&amp;#8221; style=&amp;#8221;normal&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;This is an extract from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.seecore.org/d/ais85a_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;seecore.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;ARIZ 71&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;, that is described in the book, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Innovation-Algorithm-systematic-innovation-creativity/dp/0964074044&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Innovation Algorithm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;by Genrich Altshuller. ARIZ can be used to solve problems. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tips that I have learnt from experts in the field are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARIZ is very methodical and systematic. Try to persist till you get the right solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARIZ can sometimes be painstakingly long, so if you are unable to solve your problem through other means, by all means, try those. When all else fails, use ARIZ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like with any other new technique, ARIZ requires 2 things: Practice and a mentor

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice: 80 hours in classroom like atmosphere with peers is highly recommended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the powerpoint version of ARIZ to help you with solving the problem that you have undertaken. However, a regular flipchart (A0 or A1) is highly recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, you will go through all the emotions involved in dealing with an unsolved problem &amp;#8211; some of it good, some of it not so good! Persist with the problem, if you care to solve it&amp;#8230; 🙂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll try and anticipate one question: Why ARIZ71 and not 85 or 87? First of all, ARIZ71 was written by Genrich Altshuller in 1971, hence the number 71. Second of all, ARIZ71, in my humble opinion, is worded in simpler terms than the subsequent ARIZ versions. Besides, I hear from experts that the spirit of TRIZ and ARIZ is essentially unchanged, barring a few details, in all the versions of ARIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-1-choosing-the-problem&#34;&gt;Part 1: Choosing the Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-1-determine-the-final-goal-of-a-solution&#34;&gt;Step 1-1&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Determine the final goal of a solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the technical goal (what characteristic of the object must be changed)?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What characteristic of the object obviously cannot be changed in the process of solving a problem?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the economic goal of the solution? (Which expense will be reduced if the problem is solved?)
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the roughly acceptable expense?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the main technical / economic characteristic that must be improved?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-2-bypass-approach&#34;&gt;Step 1-2: Bypass approach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate a &amp;#8220;bypass approach&amp;#8221;. Imagine that the problem, in principle, cannot be solved. What other, more general problem, can be solved to reach the required final result?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Proceed to the super-system (for the given system, from which the problem originated) and reformulate the original problem at the level of the supersystem.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Proceed to the sub-systems (the given system contains a set of subsystems) and reformulate the original problem at the level of the subsystems (e.g. substances).
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Reformulate the original problem for three levels (super-system, system, sub-system) by replacing the required action (or feature) with an opposite action (or feature).
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-3&#34;&gt;Step 1-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Determine which problem, the original or the bypass, makes the most sense to solve. Choose which to pursue: take into account the objective factors (what are the system reserves of evolution); take into account the subjective factors (which problem it is supposed to solve – mini-problem or maxi-problem).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-4&#34;&gt;Step 1-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Determine the required quantitative characteristics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-5&#34;&gt;Step 1-5.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Increase the required quantitative characteristics by considering the time for implementing the invention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-6&#34;&gt;Step 1-6.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Define the requirements of the specific conditions in which the invention is going to function.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Consider the specific conditions for manufacturing the product: in particular, the acceptable degree of complexity.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Consider the scale of future applications.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;note-this-step-is-given-in-ariz-85a-but-not-in-ariz-71&#34;&gt;[NOTE: This step is given in ARIZ 85a, but not in ARIZ 71&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-7&#34;&gt;Step 1-7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Examine if it is possible to solve the problem by direct application of the Inventive Standards. If the problem has been solved, go to 5.1. If the problem is still unsolved, go to Step 2-1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-2-defining-the-problem-more-precisely&#34;&gt;Part 2: Defining the Problem more precisely&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-1&#34;&gt;Step 2-1&lt;strong&gt;: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Define the problem more precisely using patent information.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How are problems close to the given one solved in other patents?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How are similar problems solved in leading industries?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How are opposite problems solved?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-2&#34;&gt;Step 2-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use STC operator (Size, Time, Cost).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the dimensions of an object from its given value to infinity (S → ∞). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the dimensions of an object from its given value to zero (S → 0). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the time of the process (or the speed of an object) from its given value to infinity (T → ∞). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the time of the process (or the speed of an object) from its given value to zero (T → 0). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the cost (allowed spending) of an object or process from its given value to infinity (C →∞). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the cost (allowed spending) of an object or process from its given value to zero (C → 0). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-3&#34;&gt; Step 2-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Describe the conditions of the problem (without using special terms, and without stating what exactly must be thought out, found, or developed) in two phrases using the following format:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Given a system consisting of (&lt;em&gt;describe its elements&lt;/em&gt;).&amp;#8221; Example: &amp;#8220;There is a &lt;em&gt;pipeline&lt;/em&gt; with a &lt;em&gt;valve&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Element (&lt;em&gt;state element&lt;/em&gt;), under conditions (state conditions), produces the undesirable effect (state effect).&amp;#8221; Example: &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Water&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;particles of iron ore&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;transported through this pipe&lt;/em&gt;. The particles of ore are &lt;em&gt;wearing the valve&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-4&#34;&gt;Step 2-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the elements of Step 2-3a into a table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;TYPES OF ELEMENTS&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;ELEMENTS&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      a. Elements that can be changed, redesigned, or returned (under the conditions of this problem)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      Example from above: &lt;i&gt;pipeline, valve&lt;/i&gt;.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      b. Elements that are difficult to change (under the conditions of this problem)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      Example from above: &lt;i&gt;water, ore particles&lt;/i&gt;.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-5&#34;&gt;Step 2-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose from Step 2-4a the easiest element to change, redesign, or tune. Note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If all elements in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-4a&lt;/em&gt; are equal by degree of possible changes, begin with an immobile, element (usually they are easier to change than mobile ones).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is an element in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-4a&lt;/em&gt; that is connected with an undesirable effect (usually this is indicated in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-3b&lt;/em&gt;), choose it only as the last resort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the system has only the elements in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-4b&lt;/em&gt;, take as an element the outside environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: Choose &lt;em&gt;pipeline&lt;/em&gt; because &lt;em&gt;valve&lt;/em&gt; is connected to the undesirable effect &lt;em&gt;wearing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-3-analytical-stage&#34;&gt;Part 3: Analytical Stage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-1&#34;&gt;Step 3-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formulate the IFR (Ideal Final Result) using the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the element from &lt;em&gt;Step 2-5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State its action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it performs this action (when answering this question, always use the words “by itself”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; it performs this action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: (a) Pipeline… (b) changes its cross section… &amp;copy; by itself… (d) when flow control is required… (e) without wearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-2&#34;&gt;Step 3-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Draw two pictures – (1) “Initial” (the condition before &lt;strong&gt;IFR&lt;/strong&gt;), and (2) “Ideal” (condition upon attaining &lt;strong&gt;IFR&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/em&gt; Note: The pictures may be arbitrary as long as they reflect the essences “Initial” and “Ideal”. The “Ideal” picture must reflect the written formulation of the &lt;strong&gt;IFR&lt;/strong&gt;. Test of &lt;em&gt;Step 3-2&lt;/em&gt;: All elements stated in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-3a&lt;/em&gt; must be in the picture. If the outside environment is chosen in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-5&lt;/em&gt;, it must be shown in the “ideal” section of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-3&#34;&gt;Step 3-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the “ideal” picture, find the element indicated in Step 3-1a and highlight (by a different color, or other means) that part which cannot perform the required function under the required conditions.&lt;/em&gt; Example: In our problem, the internal surface of the pipeline will be such a part&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-4&#34;&gt;Step 3-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why can this element (by itself) not perform the required action?&lt;/em&gt; Supplementary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do we expect from the highlighted area of the object?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: The internal surface of the pipe must, by itself, change its cross section in order to change the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What prevents it from performing this action by itself?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: It is immobile; therefore, it cannot separate itself from the pipe’s wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the conflict between “a” and “b” above?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: It must be &lt;em&gt;immobile&lt;/em&gt; (as an element of the rigid pipe) and &lt;em&gt;mobile&lt;/em&gt; (as a contractible and releasable element of the controller).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-5&#34;&gt;Step 3-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under what conditions can this part provide the required action? (What parameters should this part posses?)&lt;/em&gt; Note: Do not consider whether or not this is possible to realize at this time. Just name the characteristic and don’t be concerned about how it will be accomplished. Example: On the internal surface of the pipe a layer of some substance appears, bringing the internal surface closer to the axis of the pipe. When required, this layer disappears, and the internal surface moves further from the axis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-6&#34;&gt;Step 3-6:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What must be done so that this element (the internal surface of the pipe) attains the characteristic described in &lt;em&gt;Step 3-5&lt;/em&gt;? Auxiliary points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On your picture, indicate with arrows the forces that need to be applied to the highlighted part of the object in order to produce the desired characteristic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can these forces be developed? (Do not consider methods that contradict the conditions in &lt;em&gt;Step 3-1e&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: On the internal surface of the pipe, particles of iron ore or water (ice) can be grown. There are no other substances inside the pipe. This will determine our choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-7&#34;&gt;Step 3-7:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formulate a concept that can be practically realized. If there are several concepts, number them with the most promising as number one. Write down all such concepts Example: Design a section of the pipe from a non-magnetic material. Then, with the help of an electro-magnetic field, “grow” particles of iron ore on the pipe’s internal surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-8&#34;&gt;Step 3-8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provide a schematic for realizing the first concept Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the “aggregrate” (composite parts) state of the working element of the new device?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the device change during one cycle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the device change after many cycles?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating this concept, it is recommended that you return to &lt;em&gt;Step 3-7&lt;/em&gt; and consider other concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-4-preliminary-analysis-of-the-arrived-at-concept&#34;&gt;Part 4: Preliminary Analysis of the Arrived-at Concept&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-1&#34;&gt;Step 4-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is getting better, and what is getting worse, during the utilization of the new idea or concept? Write down what is achieved and what is getting more complicated or more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-2&#34;&gt;Step 4-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to prevent that which is getting worse by changing the proposed device or method? Make a drawing of the changed device or method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-3&#34;&gt;Step 4-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is getting worse (more complicated, more expensive) now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-4&#34;&gt;Step 4-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare gains and losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which is larger?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is greater gain than loss (even in the future), go to &lt;em&gt;Part Six, the Synthesis Stage of ARIZ&lt;/em&gt;. If losses are greater than gains, return to &lt;em&gt;Step 3-1&lt;/em&gt;. Record, on the same paper as the original analysis, the sequence of the secondary analysis as well as its result. Proceed to &lt;em&gt;Step 4-5&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-5&#34;&gt;Step 4-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If the gain is now greater than any losses, go to Part Six, the Synthesis Stage of ARIZ. If the secondary analysis did not produce a new result, return to Step 2-4 and check the table. Take from Step 2-5 other elements of the system and make a new analysis. Write down the second analysis and its result.&lt;/em&gt; If there is no satisfactory solution after Step 4-5, go to the next part of ARIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-5-operative-stage&#34;&gt;Part 5: Operative Stage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-1&#34;&gt;Step 5-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the vertical column of the Contradiction Matrix, choose the characteristic that must be improved.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-2&#34;&gt;Step 5-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;a.     &lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;How can we improve this characteristic (from Step 5-1) utilizing any known means (if losses are not considered)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;b.     &lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Which characteristic becomes unacceptable if a known means is used?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-3&#34;&gt;Step 5-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the horizontal row of the Contradiction Matrix, choose that characteristic corresponding to Step 5-2b.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-4&#34;&gt;Step 5-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the Matrix, find the principles for removing the technical contradiction (this means, locate the cell at the intersection of the column from Step 5-1 and the row from Step 5-3).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-5&#34;&gt;Step 5-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate how these principles can be used (we will discuss these principles in the following chapters)&lt;/em&gt; If the problem is now solved, return to Part 4 of ARIZ, evaluate the new idea, and then go to Part 6 of ARIZ. If the problem is not solved, perform the following Part 5 Steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-6&#34;&gt;Step 5-6:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate the possibility of applying physical phenomena and effects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-7&#34;&gt;Step 5-7:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate the possibility of changing the action’s point in time/duration.&lt;/em&gt; Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by “stretching” the time frame of its action?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by “shrinking” the time frame of its action?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by providing an action &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; an object finishes its operation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by providing an action &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; an object starts to operation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the process is continuous, investigate the possibility of making a transition to periodic action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the process is periodic, investigate the possibility of making a transition to continuous action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-8&#34;&gt;Step 5-8:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How are similar problems solved in nature?&lt;/em&gt; Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How have non-living parts of nature solved this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did ancient plants or animals solve this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do contemporary organisms solve this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What corrections must be made in consideration of specific new technology and materials?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-9&#34;&gt;Step 5-9:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate the possibility of making changes to those objects that operate in conjunction with ours&lt;/em&gt; Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What super-system does our system belong to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can this problem be solved if we change the super-system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the problem is still not solved, return to Step 1-3. If it is solved, return to Part 4 of ARIZ – evaluate the found idea – and then proceed to Part 6 of ARIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-1&#34;&gt;Step 6-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Determine how the super system to which our modified system belongs must be changed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-2&#34;&gt;Step 6-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore how our modified system may be used differently.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-3&#34;&gt;Step 6-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Utilize the newly found technical idea (or an idea opposite to the one found) to solve other technical problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Sauce of Innovation</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/04/the-secret-sauce-of-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 13:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/04/the-secret-sauce-of-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  TRIZ (Russian acronym for Theory of Inventive Problem Solving) has been known for many decades. Innovation for mankind has been around since fire and wheel were invented and used successfully. Prior to TRIZ and its ally ARIZ (The Algorithm of Inventive Problem Solving), inventing was best left to people who were born with such a gift (or believed they were born with such a gift). With the advent and successful implementations of TRIZ/ARIZ to solve many challenging problems, one can confidently say that inventiveness can certainly be learnt. Our own experience in the field also points to the very same conclusion. The most common (FFAQ or frequently frequently asked question) is “I have managed just fine solving problems without TRIZ/ARIZ, why should I learn something like this?”. Our (and many others like us) answer is “Good question. If you are able to solve problems on your own, please go ahead and do that, since that is the best way to solve problems. If you can’t, TRIZ can help, write to us”.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  What in the world is TRIZ/ARIZ? You might ask. we have a 10 word, 15 symbol, 8 number answer &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/2011/11/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-1-2/&#34;&gt;http://trizindia.org/2011/11/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-1-2/&lt;/a&gt;. Or better still, click the link given above.. 🙂 Please listen to &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/2011/12/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-2-2/&#34;&gt;http://trizindia.org/2011/12/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-2-2/&lt;/a&gt; also.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Once, you have applied the principles, solved many problems and you are ready to teach others how to solve these problems, there is always a problem coming your way &amp;#8211; “boy, o boy, which one of the umpteen techniques that I applied should I teach these guys to solve their problem”. Of course, you are tired of hearing the dreaded consultant “It depends” answer. Also, you don’t want to come across as a retired Colonel reciting his Victoria Cross stories to his bored lieutenants (Direct reference to Jungle Book’s Colonel Hathi). Both these options are tempting, but can have undesirable consequences on your participants. 🙂&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/Shz7sL-9aq22BAbADT2k_5-3xpG0fOK0WWSKiCZMEyDHbij4wi4NfdbDUIXV9lOBEft6hKQi9F3bZoOZvl96BLYbLscDYfv2AGRhRg0MFhl6LJ6uoyG-yum-jPuesA&#34; width=&#34;450px;&#34; height=&#34;253px;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  (Image Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.animationsource.org/sites_content/jungle_book/upload/fanchars/pic_detail4de7df4ec4fac.png&#34;&gt;http://www.animationsource.org/sites_content/jungle_book/upload/fanchars/pic_detail4de7df4ec4fac.png&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  So what can you do now? Here is a secret sauce that has worked like magic for us.&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/ppQkEUrcB3JpQQ8Okf8rTvNxfdKRfnSdYPF5kIHEg_5T1f7CiUMs_rIZtnuPeF8oLmpUIbMG60tM3rnAZITcL9g498MV7NSz3H18BMEh9Bqwc2LzL6O0-Hdh1cO85w&#34; width=&#34;532px;&#34; height=&#34;323px;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  First of all, let us give you some theory.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  In selecting TRIZ techniques for application, you are faced with 3 major dimensions (as given in the Figure, the only figure, we promise),
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  1.       The Person
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  2.       The Problem
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  3.       The Method
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Person dimension includes the nature of participant or someone who will benefit by solving the problem or resolving a contradiction. Our experience indicates participants may belong to any of the below levels
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         ‘Not for me’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         ‘I Like this’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         ‘I will apply as situation demands’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         ‘this changed my way of thinking completely’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  For TRIZ to become sustainable the more the number of people maturing to level 4, the better it is. So the first 3 levels have to be handled with care to make sure applications are easy and rigorous considering the next 2 dimensions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Problem dimension includes how certain problems need special handling, with readymade tools from TRIZ portfolio.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  e.g.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         For application around visualizing space-time, system operator (or 9 windows or 9 screens as it is fondly referred to) and an independent function analysis may well suffice
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         For imagining the ideal future, Ideal Final Result and follow up with the Size Time Cost operator may be useful
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         For resolving problems in tool/substance interactions, Substance-Field with standard solutions may be looked at
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         For pure differentiation or following possible evolution paths of systems, the Trends of Engineering Systems Evolution will be handy
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  The final dimension of Methods is mentioned here because some methods lend itself for easy combination with others. e.g.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         Immediately after doing functional analysis, time is right for trimming
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  ·         While you finish a Su-Field, looking for resources then, makes solutions cheaper and robust
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  With rigor being built into the method itself, only practice and benefiting for current contexts constantly can make TRIZ part of your company&amp;#8217;s innovation culture.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  TRIZ India is a growing community of global TRIZ and systematic innovation practitioners. At &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/&#34;&gt;TRIZ Innovation India | http://trizindia.org/&lt;/a&gt;  we cater to those that are serious about ‘how to innovate’ with ‘no barriers to entry’. With TRIZ masters and experienced facilitators across the world actively engaged in the community, TRIZ Innovation India can give the necessary impetus to your specific innovation needs.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  Resources including podcasts, pro-forma for TRIZ techniques and workbooks, facilitation tips, cross domain applications, stories and special interest groups are available for free at the community site.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
  It is ultimately a community of practice with the vision and objectives set by ‘you’ the community. Write to us, become part of the community, let us innovate together.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrizTrends 2014</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/triztrends-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 02:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/triztrends-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set in the picturesque GE Bangalore campus had some interesting pick of speakers. Thanks to GE for being a great host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter from Reliance was hyper selective with his picks with just the contradiction and principles as the approach and I liked what worked in teams from his experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course he hit the mark with India being a country of contradictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sergei shared some interesting roi numbers and gave clear idea of Triz evolution. I liked the test done with 3 contradiction matrix, as long as ideas solved problems all is well. Most popular techniques was cool. Looks like I have made my choices always popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting non technical examples resolving contradictions from art, politics, nature and religion from Sergei and Alex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debjani spoke about Triz being applied in IP field. Shankar spoke about his forever fresh innovation flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also relaunched our site in front of Triz masters and some very innovative people. Alex&amp;#8217;s definition of disruptive as creating access to new resources was spot on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CALL FOR PAPERS – TRIZ FUTURE CONFERENCE 2014</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/call-for-papers-triz-future-conference-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 09:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/03/call-for-papers-triz-future-conference-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;parent-fieldname-description&#34;&gt;
  European TRIZ Association (ETRIA) is organizing TRIZ Future Conference (TFC2014) along with Exelop SA will be hosted by EPFL Lausanne, Switzerland. TFC2014 is also sponsored by CIRP, the international Academy for Production Engineering. TFC2014 will provide an international forum for exchanging new ideas on knowledge‐ based innovation and TRIZ, presenting recent achievements by the scientific community and enabling further advances and collaboration also with the industrial community.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;viewlet-above-content-body&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;content-core&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div id=&#34;parent-fieldname-text&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;page_1&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/CALL-FOR-PAPERS-TFC20142x1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-261&#34; alt=&#34;CALL FOR PAPERS TFC20142x1&#34; src=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/CALL-FOR-PAPERS-TFC20142x1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;552&#34; height=&#34;57&#34; srcset=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/CALL-FOR-PAPERS-TFC20142x1.jpg 552w, http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/CALL-FOR-PAPERS-TFC20142x1-300x30.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 552px) 100vw, 552px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h2&gt;
        CALL FOR PAPERS
      &lt;/h2&gt;
      
      &lt;h2&gt;
        TRIZ FUTURE CONFERENCE 14
      &lt;/h2&gt;
      
      &lt;h2&gt;
        Global innovation Convention
      &lt;/h2&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &amp;nbsp;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;page_2&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Place:
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    EPFL (Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne), Switzerland
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Duration:
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    From 29th to 31th October 2014
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Cost:
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    650 EUR per participant (Further prices for students, Early birds, others are available on www.tfc14.com )
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Organizer:
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ETRIA’s TRIZ Future Conference TFC2014 is this year locally organized by Exelop SA in association with the ETRIA board and will be hosted by EPFL Lausanne – Switzerland. TFC2014 is also sponsored by CIRP, the international Academy for Production Engineering.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    The event:
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    The 3 days conference aims at linking:
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Industrialcompanies
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Research centers
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Educational organizations
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Individuals
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    to share their experience on systematic innovation and to develop research in the systematic innovation area.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    TFC2014 will provide an international forum for exchanging new ideas on knowledge‐ based innovation and TRIZ, presenting recent achievements by the scientific community and enabling further advances and collaboration also with the industrial community
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    The conference is divided into twoparts:
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Scientific Session: Professors and researchers present results on scientific studies
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Industrial Session: Professionals present results of practical experiences, best practices, and case studies
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;page_3&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;
    Abstracts
  &amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Theories, methods, tools and experiences on:
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Global Knowledge management for innovative conception
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Innovation on Servicesusing robust and systematic tools
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐TRIZ‐based or inspiredtheories, methodologies, techniques
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Patent Mining, knowledge harvesting and representing
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Any professional/industrial case study where TRIZ has played a significant role
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Further advanced Innovative, Inventive &amp;amp; creative design processes based on systematicmethods
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐IT for innovative engineering /Computer Aided Innovation (CAI)
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Knowledge Based Systematic Innovation Customized Services
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Product lifecycle management, laws of technical systemevolution
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Methodological support to Creativeand Inventive Design
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Inventiveness, creativity, innovation measurements (or assessment) based on systematicmethods
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    The subjects listed above are not limitative. They are expected to form the major themes of this TFC 2014 Conference. Submissions concerning these subjects are specifically encouraged, but all abstracts describing any aspect of systematic creative and innovative design will be given fair consideration. Authors interested in submitting abstracts are asked toupload their proposal to the conference website.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Review:
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    There will be a formal review of all abstracts.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    The abstracts must be submitted through the TFC2014 conference management system available through: www.tfc14.com and should be of a quality suitable for selection. The abstract should outline the major points of interest and novelty of the paper.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Selection of the papers will be made on the basis of the following criteria:
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐General interest of the subject
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Quality of the content
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Relevance to subjects covered by any of the two committees, namely (scientific or professional).
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Authors should indicate to which category of contribution they intend to contribute.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Submission requirements
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Interested parties are invited to submit an abstract (250 to 300 words) of their proposed paper with
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Title, along with a brief
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Name and current biography of the author/s.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Affiliation
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐Contact details (phone number, email id, mailing address with postal code and country)
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    In order to submit your paper, a link will be available soon published onwww.tfc14.com
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;page_4&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Important Deadlines
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Completing requirements of the Conference on time is critical for all presenters, conference planners and attendees, so the following deadlines are mandatory for your participation.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;table&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        Abstract due
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        15th March 2014
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        Notification of acceptance
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        30th March 2014
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        Full paper due
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        15th May 2014
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        Reviewer comments
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        30th June 2014
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        Final paperdue
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        22nd July 2014
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        Conference
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;

      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
        From 29th to 31st October 2014
      &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;
    Author Guidelines
  &amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Two different types ofpapers will be considered:
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐«Scientific papers» related to the TRIZ theory and methodological developments
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐«Practitioners papers» related to the application of Innovation methodologies
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Two lengths of papers will be distinguished:
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;« Short papers »&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    They should be at least 2 pages long (approximately 800 words), leading to 15 minutes of presentation (including Q&amp;amp;A)
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    ‐&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;« Long papers »&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    They should be at least 4 and maximum 6 pages long (approximately 2400 words), granting access to a full‐lengthpresentation (30 minutesincluding Q&amp;amp;A)
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    The finalpaper template will be available soon on &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.tfc14.com/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;www.tfc14.com&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    This flyer can be downloaded &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.format-project.eu/news/copy_of_call-for-papers-for-triz-future-conference-2014&amp;quot;&amp;gt;here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    EXELOP SA
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Route de Saint Julien 184 A, 1228 Plan‐les‐Ouates
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    GENEVE SUISSE
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
    Email : &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;mailto:info@exelop.com?subject=TFC%20Future%20Conference%202014&amp;quot;&amp;gt;info@exelop.com&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;‐ Tél: 022 556 0801
  &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Trends 2014, A Conference in GE India</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/02/triz-trends-2014-a-conference-in-ge-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 12:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/02/triz-trends-2014-a-conference-in-ge-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;nav&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#image-courtesy-http-ge-geglobalresearch-com-locations-bangalore-india&#34;&gt;(Image courtesy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&#34;&gt;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#span-style-color-993366-triz-trends-2014-span&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #993366;&#34;&gt;TRIZ Trends 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#image-courtesy-http-ge-geglobalresearch-com-locations-bangalore-india-1&#34;&gt;(Image courtesy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&#34;&gt;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#span-style-color-993366-triz-trends-2014-span-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #993366;&#34;&gt;TRIZ Trends 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-230&#34; alt=&#34;jfwtc&#34; src=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc.jpg&#34; width=&#34;996&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; srcset=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc.jpg 996w, http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc-300x108.jpg 300w, http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc-624x224.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 996px) 100vw, 996px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;image-courtesy-http-ge-geglobalresearch-com-locations-bangalore-india&#34;&gt;(Image courtesy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&#34;&gt;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John F. Welch Technology Center, Bangalore, INDIA is hosting an event on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time: Thursday &amp;#8211; March 20, 2014 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue: John F. Welch Technology Center, Bangalore, INDIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the following topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-style-color-993366-triz-trends-2014-span&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #993366;&#34;&gt;TRIZ Trends 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be invited speakers from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GE, Gen3 Partners, Reliance, Mindtree, SKF, Cummins, Target, TrizIndia Forum and TRIZ Asia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registration is FREE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please register for the event here &amp;#8211; &lt;a title=&#34;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;d=3819761&#34; href=&#34;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;d=3819761&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;amp;d=3819761&#34;&gt;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;amp;d=3819761&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LAST DATE TO REGISTER : March 5, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please download the event flyer from here &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/TRIZ-TRENDS-2014-Announcement.pdf&#34; title=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/TRIZ-TRENDS-2014-Announcement.pdf&#34;&gt;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/TRIZ-TRENDS-2014-Announcement.pdf&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-230&#34; alt=&#34;jfwtc&#34; src=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc.jpg&#34; width=&#34;996&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; srcset=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc.jpg 996w, http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc-300x108.jpg 300w, http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/jfwtc-624x224.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 996px) 100vw, 996px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;image-courtesy-http-ge-geglobalresearch-com-locations-bangalore-india-1&#34;&gt;(Image courtesy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&#34;&gt;http://ge.geglobalresearch.com/locations/bangalore-india/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John F. Welch Technology Center, Bangalore, INDIA is hosting an event on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time: Thursday &amp;#8211; March 20, 2014 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue: John F. Welch Technology Center, Bangalore, INDIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the following topic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-style-color-993366-triz-trends-2014-span-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #993366;&#34;&gt;TRIZ Trends 2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be invited speakers from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GE, Gen3 Partners, Reliance, Mindtree, SKF, Cummins, Target, TrizIndia Forum and TRIZ Asia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registration is FREE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please register for the event here &amp;#8211; &lt;a title=&#34;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;d=3819761&#34; href=&#34;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;d=3819761&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;amp;d=3819761&#34;&gt;https://supportcentral.ge.com/esurvey/takesurvey.asp?p=17778&amp;amp;d=3819761&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LAST DATE TO REGISTER : March 5, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please download the event flyer from here &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/TRIZ-TRENDS-2014-Announcement.pdf&#34; title=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/TRIZ-TRENDS-2014-Announcement.pdf&#34;&gt;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/TRIZ-TRENDS-2014-Announcement.pdf&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://trizindia.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/TRIZ-TRENDS-2014-Announcement.pdf&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of TRIZ</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/02/the-history-of-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 09:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/02/the-history-of-triz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am right now in Milan, Italy in close proximity to some of the people who have dedicated their careers to helping others solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of them is my friend and colleague, &lt;a title=&#34;Dmitry Kucharavy&#34; href=&#34;http://seecore.org/id4.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dmitry Kucharavy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple question I asked him about 2 weeks ago was &amp;#8220;What is the history of TRIZ?&amp;#8221;.Dmitry replied, &amp;#8220;I am sending you a bunch of links, where I have attempted to answer the exact same question that everybody asks me on a routine basis.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the following is an excerpt of what Dmitry sent me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRIZ: A Few Words about the History (1) (3:52)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRIZ: A Few Words about the History (2) (4:45)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRIZ: A Few Words about the History (3) (5:30)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides used in the previous presentation are given below in this link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tetris-project.org/index.php?option=com_docman&amp;task=cat_view&amp;gid=61&amp;Itemid=55&amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tetris-project.org/index.php?option=com_docman&amp;amp;task=cat_view&amp;amp;gid=61&amp;amp;Itemid=55&amp;amp;lang=en&#34;&gt;http://www.tetris-project.org/index.php?option=com_docman&amp;amp;task=cat_view&amp;amp;gid=61&amp;amp;Itemid=55&amp;amp;lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, you can also check out &lt;a title=&#34;Tetris Project&#34; href=&#34;http://www.tetris-project.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tetris-project.org&#34;&gt;http://www.tetris-project.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (A fun way to learn TRIZ. This project was headed by another colleague of mine, &lt;a href=&#34;it.linkedin.com/pub/gaetano-cascini/0/666/69&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prof. Gaetano Cascini&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next post, I&amp;#8217;ll talk about the project that I am working on currently in Milan..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9-Windows or System Operator</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/9-windows-or-system-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/9-windows-or-system-operator/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;9-windows-or-system-operator&#34;&gt;9-Windows or System Operator&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala Ramadurai, Murali Loganathan, Prakasan Kappoth and Shankar Venugopal discuss &amp;#8220;thinking out of the box&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;big picture thinking&amp;#8221; citing examples of BMW, software development, dispensing cash on the third podcast of the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:medium;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://api.ning.com/files/QHO-ed-E7o7hVvXZqsxL8oAJP3bjqfU83m8vCdRcpIqa4k6GuSf2jZnNURdjD8OPixqeezeZAIObFyCK*ajt1mkYcew3upw0/9windows.JPG&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://api.ning.com/files/QHO-ed-E7o7hVvXZqsxL8oAJP3bjqfU83m8vCdRcpIqa4k6GuSf2jZnNURdjD8OPixqeezeZAIObFyCK*ajt1mkYcew3upw0/9windows.JPG?width=750&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does a superstar plan his career moves?</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/how-does-a-superstar-plan-his-career-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/how-does-a-superstar-plan-his-career-moves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archive.org/download/HowDoesASuperstarPlanHisCareerMoves/TrizindiaPodcast9windows.mp3&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Superstar Rajinikanth&#34; src=&#34;http://www.planetradiocity.com/home/images/mr_news/rajinikanth-robot_1042011103371.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;495&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archive.org/download/HowDoesASuperstarPlanHisCareerMoves/TrizindiaPodcast9windows.mp3&#34;&gt;Triz India Podcast 9 windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala Ramadurai, Murali Loganathan, Prakasan Kappoth and Shankar Venugopal discuss &amp;#8220;thinking out of the box&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;big picture thinking&amp;#8221; citing examples of BMW, software development, dispensing cash on the third podcast of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventor in Wonderland</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/inventor-in-wonderland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/inventor-in-wonderland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRIZ podcast series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Become a member at TRIZIndia.org for FREE to connect with the world&amp;#8217;s experts on inventive problem solving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Audio Only)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtube link&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala Ramadurai, Innovation Facilitator, MindTree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar Venugopal, Innovation Leader, Honeywell, emerging markets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali Loganathan, 4 years TRIZ practitioner, across industries in MindTree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Podcast series in TRIZ tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the 1st podcast on Ideal Final Result&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Father of TRIZ &amp;#8211; Altshuller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;value addition linked to Ideal Final Result (IFR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is your experience with IFR?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar says &amp;#8211; Challenge &amp;#8211; mode of thinking into ideality &amp;#8211; common way of thinking is on constraints &amp;#8211; ideality is implementation free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali says &amp;#8211; break psychological inertia (PI) &amp;#8211; PI comes in the way of ideation. Think backwards in time &amp;#8211; put constraints in the back. Vision and mission brings grandiose picture. Thinking backward in time, one cannot lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala quotes Murali &amp;#8211; cannot lie backward in time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freeland &amp;#8211; no harm, only benefits &amp;#8211; Wonderland with only benefits &amp;#8211; problem already solved. Psychologists have proved that lying is difficult backward in time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; SCAMPER &amp;#8211; M &amp;#8211; maximize/minimize&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 steps &amp;#8211; what should be maximized or minimized? zero cost &amp;#8211; barrier to thinking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; Isak Burkhman &amp;#8211; nothing ideal or final about IFR. Free, perfect, now &amp;#8211; ideal definition for IFR. Use metaphors &amp;#8211; Wonderland is a better metaphor than IFR. Result = Process = goes forward in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heaven or Wonderland &amp;#8211; popular interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; Example &amp;#8211; Altshuller &amp;#8211; coolant leakage &amp;#8211; usual way is trial and error. What if coolant is Cindrella? Cindrella shouts out &amp;#8220;Here I am&amp;#8221;. How do you make Cindrella is visible? Turn off the lights. Then solution &amp;#8211; Coolant needs to be colour emitting and says &amp;#8220;Hi, I am here&amp;#8221;. Ideal coolant or ideal way to leak? 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; Free transport &amp;#8211; A to B? marketing campaigns lets you go from A to B for a cause &amp;#8211; global warming, travelogue writing &amp;#8211; have fun for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; Why fly? find out the reason for flying. IFR + 5 whys gives a stronger solution. Fundamental problem identified and can arrive at solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; CISCO cashed in on financial meltdown when corporates were slashing down prices &amp;#8211; different domain, different solution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/w/?v=GU0w0B2LNEE&#34;&gt;http://youtube.com/w/?v=GU0w0B2LNEE&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternate use of IFR &amp;#8211; visioning. What should my team be doing in 2014, say? who are my customers? what is their IFR? work your way backwards and write down what your team should be doing now to meet that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; customer, customer&amp;#8217;s customer, supplier &amp;#8211; all of their IFRs are different. There could be conflicts or contradictions in each others&amp;#8217; IFR. How does one solve this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; No compromise. AND is essential. customer wins AND Supplier wins. Inventive principles can help out here. First figure out IFR for all parties and solve the clash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar adds &amp;#8211; clashes are going to be standard practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; IFR + 9-windows can be combined. 9-windows spread in time and space. Mouse &amp;#8211; system, stuff around it &amp;#8211; phone, laptop, screen &amp;#8211; supersystem. Subsystem &amp;#8211; hardware wheel, software, components. All these things back in time and forward in time, what were they? You have 9-windows. System evolves from trackpad, mouse, touchscreen &amp;#8211; moves towards to an IFR. All systems/components move toward IFR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali comments on Worst Final Result (WFR) &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heaven: IFR = Hell: WFR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You find out where systems can go wrong and fix it before things go drastically wrong&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; take a pen and design a non-working pen and reverse to get a good pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; IFR in groups &amp;#8211; difficult to think of completely ideal future without accidents or lucky breaks (events). Publishing industry &amp;#8211; internet was an accident for publishing. IFR needs an accident or break. electricity and other fundamental innovations can change course of other innovation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; Accident can be looked at as an enabler. Author &amp;#8211; IFR &amp;#8211; should be able to write a book and reach the audience instantly. Reader &amp;#8211; read and access books instantly. Internet came in and enabled this. IFR can really help and accidents can be handled or enabled&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; Luckily, internet happened. George Lucas, starwars, was way ahead of his time in terms of graphics. Graphics and sound effects in the &amp;#8217;70s sucked. He later remastered the Starwars series when technology was available&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shankar &amp;#8211; do IFR for everyday objects around yourself before jumping to applying to your tech problems. Make yourself at ease&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali &amp;#8211; Add &amp;#8220;Self&amp;#8221; as a prefix to make anything ideal. That is the way to get an IFR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bala &amp;#8211; take something that you care about and apply IFR for permanent change&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next time on TRIZ podcast series from TRIZIndia.org&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What in the world is TRIZ? Part 2</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/01/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://cdnimg.visualizeus.com/thumbs/a1/72/twitter,cartoon,communication,evolution,funny,joke-a172a30347ffa67544455ec0669a6f7e_h.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The evolution of communication / Mike Keape&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ellen Domb, Prakasan Kappoth, Murali Loganathan and Bala Ramadurai discuss the finer aspects of TRIZ. A continuation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archive.org/details/WhatInTheWorldIsTrizPart1&#34;&gt;http://www.archive.org/details/WhatInTheWorldIsTrizPart1&lt;/a&gt;. The participants discuss about system evolution, system operators, creative problem solving, internal vs external consultant. . &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trizindia.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.trizindia.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.archive.org/download/WhatInTheWorldIsTrizPart2/TRIZIndia-WhatintheworldisTRIZ-part2.mp3&#34;&gt;Listen to the podcast here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:xx-small;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image Courtesy:&lt;a href=&#34;http://vi.sualize.us/view/a172a30347ffa67544455ec0669a6f7e/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vi.sualize.us/view/a172a30347ffa67544455ec0669a6f7e/&#34;&gt;http://vi.sualize.us/view/a172a30347ffa67544455ec0669a6f7e/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>