<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on TRIZ Innovation India</title>
    <link>http://trizindia.org/categories/tools/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on TRIZ Innovation India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://trizindia.org/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract from ARIZ 71 – The Algorithm of Problem Solving</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2014/05/ariz-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 11:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2014/05/ariz-71/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/preview&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/preview&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; title=&amp;#8221;ARIZ-71&amp;#8243; icon=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; width=&amp;#8221;100%&amp;#8221; height=&amp;#8221;400&amp;#8243; extra=&amp;#8221;undefined&amp;#8221; style=&amp;#8221;embed&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/edit?usp=drivesdk&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1s4sVnO2y_wfCNrzRdEXDrfYU9RkZIlVbBicSEdJL23Y/edit?usp=drivesdk&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; title=&amp;#8221;ARIZ-71&amp;#8243; icon=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&#34;&gt;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; newwindow=&amp;#8221;yes&amp;#8221; style=&amp;#8221;normal&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;This is an extract from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.seecore.org/d/ais85a_en.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;seecore.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;ARIZ 71&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;, that is described in the book, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Innovation-Algorithm-systematic-innovation-creativity/dp/0964074044&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Innovation Algorithm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;by Genrich Altshuller. ARIZ can be used to solve problems. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tips that I have learnt from experts in the field are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARIZ is very methodical and systematic. Try to persist till you get the right solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARIZ can sometimes be painstakingly long, so if you are unable to solve your problem through other means, by all means, try those. When all else fails, use ARIZ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like with any other new technique, ARIZ requires 2 things: Practice and a mentor

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice: 80 hours in classroom like atmosphere with peers is highly recommended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the powerpoint version of ARIZ to help you with solving the problem that you have undertaken. However, a regular flipchart (A0 or A1) is highly recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, you will go through all the emotions involved in dealing with an unsolved problem &amp;#8211; some of it good, some of it not so good! Persist with the problem, if you care to solve it&amp;#8230; 🙂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll try and anticipate one question: Why ARIZ71 and not 85 or 87? First of all, ARIZ71 was written by Genrich Altshuller in 1971, hence the number 71. Second of all, ARIZ71, in my humble opinion, is worded in simpler terms than the subsequent ARIZ versions. Besides, I hear from experts that the spirit of TRIZ and ARIZ is essentially unchanged, barring a few details, in all the versions of ARIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-1-choosing-the-problem&#34;&gt;Part 1: Choosing the Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-1-determine-the-final-goal-of-a-solution&#34;&gt;Step 1-1&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Determine the final goal of a solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the technical goal (what characteristic of the object must be changed)?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What characteristic of the object obviously cannot be changed in the process of solving a problem?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the economic goal of the solution? (Which expense will be reduced if the problem is solved?)
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the roughly acceptable expense?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    What is the main technical / economic characteristic that must be improved?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-2-bypass-approach&#34;&gt;Step 1-2: Bypass approach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate a &amp;#8220;bypass approach&amp;#8221;. Imagine that the problem, in principle, cannot be solved. What other, more general problem, can be solved to reach the required final result?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Proceed to the super-system (for the given system, from which the problem originated) and reformulate the original problem at the level of the supersystem.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Proceed to the sub-systems (the given system contains a set of subsystems) and reformulate the original problem at the level of the subsystems (e.g. substances).
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Reformulate the original problem for three levels (super-system, system, sub-system) by replacing the required action (or feature) with an opposite action (or feature).
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-3&#34;&gt;Step 1-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Determine which problem, the original or the bypass, makes the most sense to solve. Choose which to pursue: take into account the objective factors (what are the system reserves of evolution); take into account the subjective factors (which problem it is supposed to solve – mini-problem or maxi-problem).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-4&#34;&gt;Step 1-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Determine the required quantitative characteristics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-5&#34;&gt;Step 1-5.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Increase the required quantitative characteristics by considering the time for implementing the invention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-6&#34;&gt;Step 1-6.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Define the requirements of the specific conditions in which the invention is going to function.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Consider the specific conditions for manufacturing the product: in particular, the acceptable degree of complexity.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Consider the scale of future applications.
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;note-this-step-is-given-in-ariz-85a-but-not-in-ariz-71&#34;&gt;[NOTE: This step is given in ARIZ 85a, but not in ARIZ 71&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-7&#34;&gt;Step 1-7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Examine if it is possible to solve the problem by direct application of the Inventive Standards. If the problem has been solved, go to 5.1. If the problem is still unsolved, go to Step 2-1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_9&#34;&gt;]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-2-defining-the-problem-more-precisely&#34;&gt;Part 2: Defining the Problem more precisely&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-1&#34;&gt;Step 2-1&lt;strong&gt;: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Define the problem more precisely using patent information.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How are problems close to the given one solved in other patents?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How are similar problems solved in leading industries?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    How are opposite problems solved?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-2&#34;&gt;Step 2-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use STC operator (Size, Time, Cost).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the dimensions of an object from its given value to infinity (S → ∞). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the dimensions of an object from its given value to zero (S → 0). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the time of the process (or the speed of an object) from its given value to infinity (T → ∞). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the time of the process (or the speed of an object) from its given value to zero (T → 0). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the cost (allowed spending) of an object or process from its given value to infinity (C →∞). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Imagine changing the cost (allowed spending) of an object or process from its given value to zero (C → 0). Can this problem now be solved? If so, how?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-3&#34;&gt; Step 2-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Describe the conditions of the problem (without using special terms, and without stating what exactly must be thought out, found, or developed) in two phrases using the following format:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;a&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Given a system consisting of (&lt;em&gt;describe its elements&lt;/em&gt;).&amp;#8221; Example: &amp;#8220;There is a &lt;em&gt;pipeline&lt;/em&gt; with a &lt;em&gt;valve&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &amp;#8220;Element (&lt;em&gt;state element&lt;/em&gt;), under conditions (state conditions), produces the undesirable effect (state effect).&amp;#8221; Example: &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Water&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;particles of iron ore&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;transported through this pipe&lt;/em&gt;. The particles of ore are &lt;em&gt;wearing the valve&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-4&#34;&gt;Step 2-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the elements of Step 2-3a into a table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;TYPES OF ELEMENTS&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;ELEMENTS&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      a. Elements that can be changed, redesigned, or returned (under the conditions of this problem)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      Example from above: &lt;i&gt;pipeline, valve&lt;/i&gt;.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      b. Elements that are difficult to change (under the conditions of this problem)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td valign=&#34;top&#34; width=&#34;312&#34;&gt;
      Example from above: &lt;i&gt;water, ore particles&lt;/i&gt;.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-5&#34;&gt;Step 2-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose from Step 2-4a the easiest element to change, redesign, or tune. Note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If all elements in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-4a&lt;/em&gt; are equal by degree of possible changes, begin with an immobile, element (usually they are easier to change than mobile ones).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is an element in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-4a&lt;/em&gt; that is connected with an undesirable effect (usually this is indicated in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-3b&lt;/em&gt;), choose it only as the last resort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the system has only the elements in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-4b&lt;/em&gt;, take as an element the outside environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: Choose &lt;em&gt;pipeline&lt;/em&gt; because &lt;em&gt;valve&lt;/em&gt; is connected to the undesirable effect &lt;em&gt;wearing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-3-analytical-stage&#34;&gt;Part 3: Analytical Stage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-1&#34;&gt;Step 3-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formulate the IFR (Ideal Final Result) using the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the element from &lt;em&gt;Step 2-5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State its action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it performs this action (when answering this question, always use the words “by itself”)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; it performs this action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: (a) Pipeline… (b) changes its cross section… &amp;copy; by itself… (d) when flow control is required… (e) without wearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-2&#34;&gt;Step 3-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Draw two pictures – (1) “Initial” (the condition before &lt;strong&gt;IFR&lt;/strong&gt;), and (2) “Ideal” (condition upon attaining &lt;strong&gt;IFR&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/em&gt; Note: The pictures may be arbitrary as long as they reflect the essences “Initial” and “Ideal”. The “Ideal” picture must reflect the written formulation of the &lt;strong&gt;IFR&lt;/strong&gt;. Test of &lt;em&gt;Step 3-2&lt;/em&gt;: All elements stated in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-3a&lt;/em&gt; must be in the picture. If the outside environment is chosen in &lt;em&gt;Step 2-5&lt;/em&gt;, it must be shown in the “ideal” section of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-3&#34;&gt;Step 3-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the “ideal” picture, find the element indicated in Step 3-1a and highlight (by a different color, or other means) that part which cannot perform the required function under the required conditions.&lt;/em&gt; Example: In our problem, the internal surface of the pipeline will be such a part&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-4&#34;&gt;Step 3-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why can this element (by itself) not perform the required action?&lt;/em&gt; Supplementary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do we expect from the highlighted area of the object?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: The internal surface of the pipe must, by itself, change its cross section in order to change the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What prevents it from performing this action by itself?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: It is immobile; therefore, it cannot separate itself from the pipe’s wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the conflict between “a” and “b” above?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: It must be &lt;em&gt;immobile&lt;/em&gt; (as an element of the rigid pipe) and &lt;em&gt;mobile&lt;/em&gt; (as a contractible and releasable element of the controller).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-5&#34;&gt;Step 3-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Under what conditions can this part provide the required action? (What parameters should this part posses?)&lt;/em&gt; Note: Do not consider whether or not this is possible to realize at this time. Just name the characteristic and don’t be concerned about how it will be accomplished. Example: On the internal surface of the pipe a layer of some substance appears, bringing the internal surface closer to the axis of the pipe. When required, this layer disappears, and the internal surface moves further from the axis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-6&#34;&gt;Step 3-6:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What must be done so that this element (the internal surface of the pipe) attains the characteristic described in &lt;em&gt;Step 3-5&lt;/em&gt;? Auxiliary points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On your picture, indicate with arrows the forces that need to be applied to the highlighted part of the object in order to produce the desired characteristic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can these forces be developed? (Do not consider methods that contradict the conditions in &lt;em&gt;Step 3-1e&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: On the internal surface of the pipe, particles of iron ore or water (ice) can be grown. There are no other substances inside the pipe. This will determine our choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-7&#34;&gt;Step 3-7:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formulate a concept that can be practically realized. If there are several concepts, number them with the most promising as number one. Write down all such concepts Example: Design a section of the pipe from a non-magnetic material. Then, with the help of an electro-magnetic field, “grow” particles of iron ore on the pipe’s internal surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-8&#34;&gt;Step 3-8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provide a schematic for realizing the first concept Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the “aggregrate” (composite parts) state of the working element of the new device?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the device change during one cycle?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the device change after many cycles?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating this concept, it is recommended that you return to &lt;em&gt;Step 3-7&lt;/em&gt; and consider other concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-4-preliminary-analysis-of-the-arrived-at-concept&#34;&gt;Part 4: Preliminary Analysis of the Arrived-at Concept&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-1&#34;&gt;Step 4-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is getting better, and what is getting worse, during the utilization of the new idea or concept? Write down what is achieved and what is getting more complicated or more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-2&#34;&gt;Step 4-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to prevent that which is getting worse by changing the proposed device or method? Make a drawing of the changed device or method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-3&#34;&gt;Step 4-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is getting worse (more complicated, more expensive) now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-4&#34;&gt;Step 4-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare gains and losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which is larger?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is greater gain than loss (even in the future), go to &lt;em&gt;Part Six, the Synthesis Stage of ARIZ&lt;/em&gt;. If losses are greater than gains, return to &lt;em&gt;Step 3-1&lt;/em&gt;. Record, on the same paper as the original analysis, the sequence of the secondary analysis as well as its result. Proceed to &lt;em&gt;Step 4-5&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-5&#34;&gt;Step 4-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If the gain is now greater than any losses, go to Part Six, the Synthesis Stage of ARIZ. If the secondary analysis did not produce a new result, return to Step 2-4 and check the table. Take from Step 2-5 other elements of the system and make a new analysis. Write down the second analysis and its result.&lt;/em&gt; If there is no satisfactory solution after Step 4-5, go to the next part of ARIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-5-operative-stage&#34;&gt;Part 5: Operative Stage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-1&#34;&gt;Step 5-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the vertical column of the Contradiction Matrix, choose the characteristic that must be improved.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-2&#34;&gt;Step 5-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;a.     &lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;How can we improve this characteristic (from Step 5-1) utilizing any known means (if losses are not considered)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;b.     &lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Which characteristic becomes unacceptable if a known means is used?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-3&#34;&gt;Step 5-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the horizontal row of the Contradiction Matrix, choose that characteristic corresponding to Step 5-2b.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-4&#34;&gt;Step 5-4:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the Matrix, find the principles for removing the technical contradiction (this means, locate the cell at the intersection of the column from Step 5-1 and the row from Step 5-3).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-5&#34;&gt;Step 5-5:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate how these principles can be used (we will discuss these principles in the following chapters)&lt;/em&gt; If the problem is now solved, return to Part 4 of ARIZ, evaluate the new idea, and then go to Part 6 of ARIZ. If the problem is not solved, perform the following Part 5 Steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-6&#34;&gt;Step 5-6:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate the possibility of applying physical phenomena and effects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-7&#34;&gt;Step 5-7:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate the possibility of changing the action’s point in time/duration.&lt;/em&gt; Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by “stretching” the time frame of its action?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by “shrinking” the time frame of its action?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by providing an action &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; an object finishes its operation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it possible to remove a contradiction by providing an action &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; an object starts to operation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the process is continuous, investigate the possibility of making a transition to periodic action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the process is periodic, investigate the possibility of making a transition to continuous action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-8&#34;&gt;Step 5-8:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How are similar problems solved in nature?&lt;/em&gt; Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How have non-living parts of nature solved this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did ancient plants or animals solve this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do contemporary organisms solve this problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What corrections must be made in consideration of specific new technology and materials?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-9&#34;&gt;Step 5-9:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigate the possibility of making changes to those objects that operate in conjunction with ours&lt;/em&gt; Auxiliary questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What super-system does our system belong to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can this problem be solved if we change the super-system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the problem is still not solved, return to Step 1-3. If it is solved, return to Part 4 of ARIZ – evaluate the found idea – and then proceed to Part 6 of ARIZ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-1&#34;&gt;Step 6-1:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Determine how the super system to which our modified system belongs must be changed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-2&#34;&gt;Step 6-2:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore how our modified system may be used differently.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-3&#34;&gt;Step 6-3:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Utilize the newly found technical idea (or an idea opposite to the one found) to solve other technical problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>triz40</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2012/05/triz40/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 19:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2012/05/triz40/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone knows what happened with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.triz40.com?&#34;&gt;www.triz40.com?&lt;/a&gt; Is down. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of TRIZ Contradiction Matrix : Articles</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2012/03/evolution-of-triz-contradiction-matrix-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2012/03/evolution-of-triz-contradiction-matrix-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the LINKED_IN discussion with multiple links highlighting evolution of TRIZ contradiction matrix. The ARIZ 85 C, Darrel mann&amp;#8217;s article on upgraded matrix and Sciencedirect paper on STEPS (Systematic Tool for Efficient Problem Solving) are worth reading articles. Hope this will help you to get latest updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lnkd.in/BgdRKB&#34;&gt;http://lnkd.in/BgdRKB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new arsenal to fight old enemies</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2012/03/a-new-arsenal-to-fight-old-enemies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 16:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2012/03/a-new-arsenal-to-fight-old-enemies/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;span-style-font-family-arial-helvetica-sans-serif-class-font-size-2-a-href-http-www-thehindu-com-sci-tech-agriculture-article2964302-ece-target-blank-a-new-arsenal-to-fight-old-enemies-by-martin-a-recently-in-the-hindu-is-one-of-the-extreme-examples-of-resources-something-that-is-available-for-free-and-has-potential-utility-that-i-have-seen-i-am-reproducing-the-article-below-with-em-strong-emphasis-strong-em-on-resources-check-it-out-the-frequency-of-resource-occurring-in-our-mind-is-possibly-higher-only-if-we-pay-attention-deliberately-span-detail-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;&#34; class=&#34;font-size-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/agriculture/article2964302.ece&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A new arsenal to fight old enemies by Martin&lt;/a&gt; recently in The Hindu is one of the extreme examples of Resources (something that is available for free and has potential utility)  that I have seen. I am reproducing the article below with &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;emphasis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; on Resources, check it out. The frequency of resource occurring in our mind is possibly higher only if we pay attention deliberately. &lt;/span&gt; {.detail-title}&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;articleLead&#34;&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A farmer in Nilampur puts to good use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;FM radio broadcasts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; against wild boar raids on her yam and tapioca farm
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  What do &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;detergent cakes, abandoned compact discs, sardines, FM radio broadcasts and good old garlic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; have in common?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  They are part of a new arsenal being built by farmers across Kerala to fight old enemies that include wild boars and hares; stem borers and rice sappers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  Farmers have come up with new concoctions and found new applications for things of everyday use such as &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;plastic bags, used rubber tyres and old cotton saris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, robustly vouched for by a new compendium of farm knowledge.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  Running into more than 30 print pages, it is the fruit of an elaborate exercise by &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudumbashree poverty eradication mission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, credited with providing the blueprint for the National Rural Livelihood Mission (NRLM) and its sub-programme Mahila Kisan Sashaktikaran Pariyojana (MKSP).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  Compiling the tome took more than &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;six months&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and involved &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;68,000 women farmers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in 699 panchayats, who were brought together to share their best practices. With scribes in toe, every word was taken down for posterity.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  In its present form, Nattarivu (literally, local knowledge) stands on its own and endorses the need for thinking out of the box and adopting a hands-on approach to common and varied problems.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  Stringing up &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;old compact discs using abandoned cloth around a plot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; can considerably reduce attacks by wild boars, say farmers in Kozhikode. A ‘savoury&amp;#8217; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mix of cement and fried rice flour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a rat-killer without parallel, say farmers in Wayanad.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  They also found that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;music from mobile phones&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; drives away animals just as &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cotton balls soaked in jaggery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; liquid are traps easily taken in by rats.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow boards smeared with castor oil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are effective fly traps, say farmers in Thrissur.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  Their counterparts in Ernakulam found the slurry from a mixture of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sardines and jaggery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, seasoned over &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;45 days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, effective against pests in root crops.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;body&#34;&gt;
  Reena Gijo, a farmer in Nilampur puts to good use &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FM radio broadcasts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; against wild boar raids on her yam and tapioca farm. She says that the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;endless chatter on FM radio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; makes the animals a little cagey. And, the word is spreading.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Level Engineering: Thanks to TRIZ India</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2012/02/next-level-engineering-thanks-to-triz-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2012/02/next-level-engineering-thanks-to-triz-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
  What  Engineers must need to know today ?
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
   
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Reiterating the words from Management Guru Peter Ducker
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
   
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8221; Teach them what they  don’t know today if you want to achieve phenomenal success tomorrow&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
   
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
   With reference to image below and with respect to my observation, engineers today are doing brilliant job at providing engineering solutions and  optimization studies. But there is hardly any drive for Innovation. Certainly not because they are not capable!  It’s because they are trained mostly  on engineering solution and optimization algorithms in academics. 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Optimization strikes a compromising balance between two functional requirements  whereas innovation eliminates compromises by resolving contradictions. As an example there is a  trade-off between Power and Mileage in a car ( I hope you agree to this). Optimization mindset will tune engine and vehicle parameters to maximize power and mileage only to learn that they can&amp;#8217;t be achieved simultaneously to the highest levels. But it takes innovation mindset to think of Hybird car which provides high Power as well as high Mileage at the same time. 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  The Good news is,  there exists definite laws and principles to eliminate underlying contradiction in the system. Developing engineers through all four stages (refer image again) will intelligently transform customer voices to right products ultimately leading to  individual and business  success.  Executing innovation is what I would like to call &lt;strong&gt;Next Level Engineering!&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks to TRIZ India to take first  step in this direction.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;blogs/6-NLE.PNG&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;align-center&#34; src=&#34;blogs/7-NLE.PNG&#34; width=&#34;341&#34; height=&#34;365&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical TRIZ Workshop Resources Workbook &#43; Presentation &#43; Reference</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2012/02/practical-triz-workshop-resources-workbook-presentation-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 06:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2012/02/practical-triz-workshop-resources-workbook-presentation-reference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had given out a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1QJ_2d1vmc_Y_X8yjyTfXNUD77hJjUGxUFv6tY4KJJgg/edit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TRIZ India Workbook&lt;/a&gt; with enough space to doodle, brainstorm and use the specific guidelines on techniques used. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the appendix with the Business and Management Contradiction Matrix can be referred on  Darrell Mann reference, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Hands-Systematic-Innovation-Business-Management/dp/1898546738/ref=sr_1_5?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1330324587&amp;sr=8-5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;available on amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had also used  &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1b1aIYt2u1CsqW0gbFMageAqvLp6lnd7lsKW8cmjjESY/edit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TRIZ India Workshop Presentation&lt;/a&gt; , typical structure that we had for techniques is as follows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the basic theory or other basis behind the technique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a strong story where it was applied from either a personal experience or from other sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;personal/individual application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;group application and facilitation notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we saw tremendous enthusiasm from industry (across IT, Oil and Gas, Energy, Pharma, Engineering in this workshop alone) we hope to get broader participation from academia as well. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chennai workshop is coming up in March, we could come to your city too if there is a critical strength and participation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Road trip anyone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions/Comments welcome&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website runs without internet..Trim the most important function or resource</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2012/01/website-runs-without-internet-trim-the-most-important-function-or-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 05:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2012/01/website-runs-without-internet-trim-the-most-important-function-or-resource/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Re-post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://trizit.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;http://trizit.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ok; this is for those who follow South Indian films and also know the &amp;#8220;super star&amp;#8221; in the Tamil movie industry, Rajinikanth. Do Google about him to know his super star power (in movies) and read some PJ&amp;#8217;s about him. But this is interesting, and not a joke, that his website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allaboutrajni.com&#34;&gt;www.allaboutrajni.com&lt;/a&gt; runs when there is no internet (a very simple solution technically)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Read more about it here..
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thehindu.com/arts/cinema/article2818048.ece&#34;&gt;http://www.thehindu.com/arts/cinema/article2818048.ece&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Well, no technological break through. Your browsers will get you the wesbite only when you have an internet connection, but to browse Rajini sirs website, you should disconnect your internet, before you disconnected the internet they would have downloaded a flash file and it will work only after it identifies no internet connection.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  Coming to some interesting observation (I saw the comments in the Facebook posting where I got this from), and using Rajini&amp;#8217;s power in other context and use Trimming.The most important ingredient of a website we take it granted is internet. Now, can we remove (trim down) this important resource required for a website? What if the same concepts used in all important website around us, especially for the rural areas of developing countries like India and yet to be developed countries where there is no power (or power only for few hours), internet is available like ration?
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  I have read some interesting innovations similar to this where this kind of offline websites are syncd with servers twice a day in rural areas when a vehicle fit with the remote satellite connection pass through the villages. Now, we probably have better resources like mobile phone. How about a mobile mesh network connecting to this offline website and the realtime information is available through simple txt (SMS). The mobile mesh is again created by using your and my cell phones in the rural area..
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  More ideas?
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple rule of Innovating Technology</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2011/09/a-simple-rule-of-innovating-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 15:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2011/09/a-simple-rule-of-innovating-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inline with TRIZ Principle, we can devise a simple rule to understand and appreciate any product or technology we come across.  I mentioned about the rule and it&amp;#8217;s application for Automotive technologies at the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you will like it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://smartfundas.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;http://smartfundas.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Seperation Principle: Maximizing Trasport Service Revenue and Passenger Convenience</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2011/09/triz-seperation-principle-maximizing-trasport-service-revenue-and-passenger-convenience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2011/09/triz-seperation-principle-maximizing-trasport-service-revenue-and-passenger-convenience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;**&lt;br /&gt;
**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in Pune I am just taking the case of local public bus transport however I am sure this applies to any general transport meant for public. The public road transport service (PMPML) in Pune although wide spread across the city is not the certainly the most profitable with it&amp;#8217;s fixed frequency schedule and  a  assumption that affordability of this transport is same for all commuters from all sections and classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the peak traffic periods, where demand exceeds the supply leading to overloaded, inconvenient and unsafe travels. And yes..around 40% of potential commuters hire rickshaws with a affordability 10 times more than PMPML fare. If I have to think it from business perspective, people preferring other modes of expensive transport are PMPML&amp;#8217;s potential customers and they preferring other mode of (expensive) transport is direct loss of revenue for PMPML. Secondly the frequency for buses is fixed so they run&lt;br /&gt;
deserted in the non-peak and overloaded during peaks. PMPML has tremendous opportunity to increase it’s revenue and passenger convenience at the same time.  The key is to segment the market  and provide different service standards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Reduce the frequency during non-peak hours and increase it during peak &lt;strong&gt;(Seperation in Time)&lt;/strong&gt; with three bus types as below &lt;strong&gt;(Separation in Space)&lt;/strong&gt;. Management terminology may want to call this **Market Segmentation&lt;br /&gt;
**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211;  Convert regular buses to Type 1 buses with no seats (only standing)   for covering the peaks. This will increase the capacity of bus by atleast by 30% (and hence revenue even if fare is cut down by 10%). The convenience is same for all passengers. In the regular buses we see 60% seating passengers occupy 80% bus area and rest 40% standing get remaining 20%.   Fast commuters don’t want seat. They will prefer to stand when they know it is  fast , safe and low cost&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Convert regular buses  to Type 2 with better seats , cleanliness, promptness in service, fixed schedules, prior reservation etc.  Charge at least 3 times Type 1 buses (high revenue again).  It won’t be surprise if it is occupied by Sr. citizens, ladies , non rushing  and occasional commuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Have Type 3 which are regular buses running today on the road. It can accommodate all types commuters happily but only during non-peaks. The fare could be little higher than Type 1 buses again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   Once we understand the  crowd density, class of people and peak hours for particular route the type ,frequency and number of  buses can be accordingly  optimized to maximize the revenue and passenger convenience simultaneously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There could be an argument that it will increase complexity and cost. The answer is cost increase can be minimized if buses schedules and types are optimized across the city. If at all there is cost increase for additional buses, the additional profit should cover it up in long term (Payback period may not be too long). And complexity due to different type of buses will be compensated by flexibility inside people to choose different buses at different times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this makes social and business sense!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What would a Bumble Bee do ?</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2011/09/what-would-a-bumble-bee-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 16:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2011/09/what-would-a-bumble-bee-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look at your Problem through different lenses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to come up with innovative ideas is to look at a problem innovatively i.e look at the problem through different lenses. We tend to look at a problem from only one angle &amp;#8211; but how to trigger our mind to look at it from different angles ? Try asking the question what would X do &amp;#8211; X could be Steve Jobs or Buddha or Don Quixote or Gandhi or your own Grandfather or Mother-in-law &amp;#8211; the idea is to bring a new perspective to the problem. I listed 100+ such people &amp;#8211; studied their innovative thinking style &amp;#8211; and asked myself &amp;#8220;What would X do?&amp;#8221; to create a new perspective to the problem that I work on. I conciously limit this exercise only to define the problem &amp;#8211; i do not extend this concept to idea generation (for certain reasons that i will elaborate later). When you try to solve a problem innovatively, a trigger that you could use is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;What would a Bumble Bee do?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&#34;_self&#34; href=&#34;blogs/12-bumblebee.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;128&#34; src=&#34;blogs/13-bumblebee.jpg&#34; class=&#34;align-full&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bumble Bee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to 20th century folklore, the laws of aerodynamics prove that the bumble bee should be incapable of flight, as it does not have the capacity (in terms of wing size or beats per second) to achieve flight with the degree of wing loading necessary. The origin of this claim has been difficult to pin down with any certainty (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bumble_bee&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bumble_bee&lt;/a&gt;). So Science said that the bumblebee can not fly. But luckily it the bumble bee did not know that. That is why it flies ! I am reminded here of Arthur Clarke (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Arthur_C._Clarke&#34;&gt;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Arthur_C._Clarke&lt;/a&gt; ) Clarke&amp;#8217;s First Law: When a distinguished but elderly scientist states that something is possible, he is almost certainly right. When he states that something is impossible, he is very probably wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovation Lesson from Bumble Bee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep the Experts away from your early brainstorming sessions if you dont want your new ideas to get killed. So if you are a bumble bee you would not be biased by conventional wisdom or bogged down by what the expert say. You will just go ahead and make your new idea work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applying the funda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;List down a four or five things that conventional wisdom in that domain says and reverse each one of those statements. Brainstorm around these reversed statements and jot down the ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Conventional wisdom says that to run a good School, we need good teachers. But what do we do if we cant find good teachers? Reversed statement is we can run a good school without good teachers. A bumble bee would not be worried by lack of good teachers &amp;#8211; it will just go ahead and run the school. Brainstorm how to run a school without teachers &amp;#8211; experiential learning, student teachers, elearning, run videos etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image courtesy: wpclipart.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Future Air Travel and Principle 16</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2010/01/our-future-air-travel-and-principle-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 16:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2010/01/our-future-air-travel-and-principle-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;blogs/26-AirlineSeat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airline business makes its revenue and in turn profit per seat per mile flown. Naturally it is in their best interest to put more seats in the aircraft and the airline manufacturers have to oblige to see that its customers remain profitable. From 31 inch it may be reduced in future to 25 inch to accommodate more passengers. I recollect Principle 16 Partial or Excessive Action which reads “ If exactly the right amount of action is hard to achieve , use “ slightly less” or “slightly more” of the action, to reduce or eliminate the problem”. Now seating ( Slightly Less) &amp;amp; standing ( Slightly More) what we consider as actions then the principle 16 perfectly fits in here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pictures below speak comparison, so will not be explicit. These days people take blogs and Tweets seriously, if only it’s politically correct for them, I hope you know what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;blogs/27-HensTransportInIndia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Both Hand Drive, Malishkagiri &amp; TRIZ</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 18:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some TRIZ Humour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Both Hand Drive, Malishkagiri &amp; TRIZ</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 18:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some TRIZ Humour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forkless Bicycle</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2009/11/forkless-bicycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 08:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2009/11/forkless-bicycle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent invention by a designer. It is a bicycle without the front fork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By removing the assumption that a front fork is necessary he forced himself to think of other ways to control the bicycle.[&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/7qiR7E3dpjk&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;never&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8221; target=&amp;#8221;_blank&amp;#8221;&amp;gt;]&lt;a href=&#34;%3Cobject%20width=&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard Solutions</title>
      <link>http://trizindia.org/2009/11/standard-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 20:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://trizindia.org/2009/11/standard-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, We are trying to make an innovative design for a wheelchair and we have identified some physical contradictions. We are trying to find some references about the standard solutions of TRIZ . Anyone has an idea where to find them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks in advanced&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adrian&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>