<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justrizin on TRIZ Innovation India</title>
    <link>https://trizindia.org/categories/justrizin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Justrizin on TRIZ Innovation India</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 09:59:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trizindia.org/categories/justrizin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Vladimir Petrov, a TRIZ Master</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2015/10/interview-with-vladimir-petrov-a-triz-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 09:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2015/10/interview-with-vladimir-petrov-a-triz-master/</guid>
      <description>Vladimir Petrov (Profile here &amp;#8211; ) has been an avid supporter of TRIZ Innovation India and has always volunteered to spread awareness of TRIZ in India, which is the mission of TRIZ Innovation India. His simple reply to my email was &amp;#8220;How can I help TRIZ India?&amp;#8221;. I present excerpts from our online interview, which was the result of his offer of help.
Bala Ramadurai: From your track record, you have not only taught TRIZ, but also practically used it, as is obvious from your publications and patents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Glossary Book</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2015/09/triz-glossary-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 07:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2015/09/triz-glossary-book/</guid>
      <description>{.null} TRIZ Glossary book written by Prof. Vladimir Petrov is now available at an introductory price of USD 0.99 in the link given below. Prof. Petrov&amp;#8217;s linkedin profile is here &amp;#8211; https://il.linkedin.com/pub/vladimir-petrov-triz/6/30a/700
The link to the book is given here &amp;#8211;
http://www.amazon.in/TRIZ-Glossary-Vladimir-Petrov-ebook/dp/B013YE59M2/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1441695997&amp;amp;sr=1-1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Forecasting – A Primer</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/06/technology-forecasting-a-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 09:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/06/technology-forecasting-a-primer/</guid>
      <description>I promised a while ago that I&amp;#8217;d publish something about Technology Forecasting, which is my current occupation in Milan, Italy. I presented a talk on technology forecasting in Politecnico di Milano. I have attached the slideshow to this post. Enjoy!
Please feel free to download the presentation [google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;https://docs.google.com/uc?id=0B3EZPxN_ojAfTV9aazdCRWx1Rms&amp;amp;export=download&amp;amp;#8221; title=&amp;#8221;2013_03_08_Bala_Ramadurai-Technology Forecasting.pptx&amp;#8221; icon=&amp;#8221;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_10_powerpoint_list.png&amp;amp;#8221; style=&amp;#8221;download&amp;#8221;]
[google-drive-embed url=&amp;#8221;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fsSr-IG9tO99z5Zb0eht2nTwcWtvfnOaJjsZVfl2hvI/preview&amp;amp;#8221; title=&amp;#8221;2013_03_08_Bala_Ramadurai-Technology Forecasting&amp;#8221; icon=&amp;#8221;https://ssl.gstatic.com/docs/doclist/images/icon_11_presentation_list.png&amp;amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;100%&amp;#8221; height=&amp;#8221;400&amp;#8243; style=&amp;#8221;embed&amp;#8221;]
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIZ 85C algorithm application introduction</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/04/ariz-85c-algorithm-application-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 02:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/04/ariz-85c-algorithm-application-introduction/</guid>
      <description>I am a parent with 2 kids and I am finding it difficult to control the amount of non-school time they are spending on the internet and digital mobile games. This I am concerned with considering the effects of such engagement on the kids holistic development and well being (body, mind and social development). We (me and my friend Bala) are applying ARIZ 85 C core algorithm of TRIZ to find the right level of problem to attack and find not-so-obvious solutions, and subsequently identify system, and sub-systems to build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Sauce of Innovation</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/04/the-secret-sauce-of-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 13:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/04/the-secret-sauce-of-innovation/</guid>
      <description>TRIZ (Russian acronym for Theory of Inventive Problem Solving) has been known for many decades. Innovation for mankind has been around since fire and wheel were invented and used successfully. Prior to TRIZ and its ally ARIZ (The Algorithm of Inventive Problem Solving), inventing was best left to people who were born with such a gift (or believed they were born with such a gift). With the advent and successful implementations of TRIZ/ARIZ to solve many challenging problems, one can confidently say that inventiveness can certainly be learnt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/02/the-history-of-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 09:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/02/the-history-of-triz/</guid>
      <description>I am right now in Milan, Italy in close proximity to some of the people who have dedicated their careers to helping others solve problems.
One of them is my friend and colleague, Dmitry Kucharavy.
The simple question I asked him about 2 weeks ago was &amp;#8220;What is the history of TRIZ?&amp;#8221;.Dmitry replied, &amp;#8220;I am sending you a bunch of links, where I have attempted to answer the exact same question that everybody asks me on a routine basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9-Windows or System Operator</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/9-windows-or-system-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/9-windows-or-system-operator/</guid>
      <description>9-Windows or System Operator Bala Ramadurai, Murali Loganathan, Prakasan Kappoth and Shankar Venugopal discuss &amp;#8220;thinking out of the box&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;big picture thinking&amp;#8221; citing examples of BMW, software development, dispensing cash on the third podcast of the series.
&amp;nbsp;

&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does a superstar plan his career moves?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/how-does-a-superstar-plan-his-career-moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/how-does-a-superstar-plan-his-career-moves/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;

Triz India Podcast 9 windows
Bala Ramadurai, Murali Loganathan, Prakasan Kappoth and Shankar Venugopal discuss &amp;#8220;thinking out of the box&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;big picture thinking&amp;#8221; citing examples of BMW, software development, dispensing cash on the third podcast of the series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventor in Wonderland</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/inventor-in-wonderland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/inventor-in-wonderland/</guid>
      <description>TRIZ podcast series
Become a member at TRIZIndia.org for FREE to connect with the world&amp;#8217;s experts on inventive problem solving
(Audio Only)
Youtube link
Bala Ramadurai, Innovation Facilitator, MindTree
Shankar Venugopal, Innovation Leader, Honeywell, emerging markets
Murali Loganathan, 4 years TRIZ practitioner, across industries in MindTree
Podcast series in TRIZ tools
This is the 1st podcast on Ideal Final Result
Father of TRIZ &amp;#8211; Altshuller
value addition linked to Ideal Final Result (IFR)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What in the world is TRIZ? Part 2</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ellen Domb, Prakasan Kappoth, Murali Loganathan and Bala Ramadurai discuss the finer aspects of TRIZ. A continuation from http://www.archive.org/details/WhatInTheWorldIsTrizPart1. The participants discuss about system evolution, system operators, creative problem solving, internal vs external consultant. . http://www.trizindia.org
Listen to the podcast here
Image Courtesy:http://vi.sualize.us/view/a172a30347ffa67544455ec0669a6f7e/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What in the world is TRIZ? Part 1</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 09:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2014/01/what-in-the-world-is-triz-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Image Courtesy: triz.co.uk
What is TRIZ? What does it take to start learning TRIZ and master the method? Listen to 3 people &amp;#8211; Dr. Ellen Domb, Prakasan Kappoth and Bala Ramadurai, talk about the basics of the method. http://www.trizindia.org
Listen to the podcast here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges for implementing TRIZ in India</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2013/09/challenges-for-implementing-triz-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 03:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2013/09/challenges-for-implementing-triz-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Dear All TRIZ Masters and TRIZniks
 What are the challenges for implementing TRIZ in India?
 Lack of patriotism
 Brain drain
 Chaturvarnyam (Treating people on 4 categories a. Brahmins who perform rituals to please God, b. Warriors, c. Traders d. Workers
 abuse of drugs, cigarette, ganja, liquor
 Corruption &amp;#8211; an after effect of #4 above
 Resistance to mindset change
 Believing that products from other countries are good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Innovation Method for our Productivity Puzzle</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2013/03/structured-innovation-method-for-our-productivity-puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2013/03/structured-innovation-method-for-our-productivity-puzzle/</guid>
      <description>We have been engaged in a java based development project where the development process is well defined and stream lined. We had already optimized the development process to a fairly optimal level and automated some key areas of development that gave us a good productivity boost.
However the productivity levels achieved with all the process optimization and the automations we adopted were still not sufficient to meet the deadlines, we would be behind schedule by nearly a month if the same productivity was carried forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing: Analogy to Automotive</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/11/cloud-computing-analogy-to-automotive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/11/cloud-computing-analogy-to-automotive/</guid>
      <description>Read about Cloud Computing and learnt that it is a solution which seperates the function of computing (Heavy Lifting job) and Display. This is like combining / integrating CPU of all the computers to form a Cloud and providing user with only User interface connected to Cloud through internet. This reduces the Cost as user will only pay for services (ex: 3D modelling) being used with hourly based rates. Second , size of devises is reduced as it&amp;#8217;s function is to only display information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome – 500th Member</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/08/welcome-500th-member/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 03:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/08/welcome-500th-member/</guid>
      <description>Dear All TRIZINdian friends
 I too welcome the 500th Member to this group.
One suggestion:
When you are recording the audio for publishing in the site, let the participant prepare the write up and read from it. Otherwise lot of extra noise (like yea.. ) arises and the user will not be able to grasp the content.
 Best Regards
Joseph  Mindset Solutions India
 S M S I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>triz40</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/05/triz40/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 19:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/05/triz40/</guid>
      <description>Anyone knows what happened with www.triz40.com? Is down. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of TRIZ Contradiction Matrix : Articles</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/03/evolution-of-triz-contradiction-matrix-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/03/evolution-of-triz-contradiction-matrix-articles/</guid>
      <description>Hi All,
Here is the LINKED_IN discussion with multiple links highlighting evolution of TRIZ contradiction matrix. The ARIZ 85 C, Darrel mann&amp;#8217;s article on upgraded matrix and Sciencedirect paper on STEPS (Systematic Tool for Efficient Problem Solving) are worth reading articles. Hope this will help you to get latest updates.
 http://lnkd.in/BgdRKB</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple Problem…but not able to think through TRIZ Principles</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/03/a-simple-problem-but-not-able-to-think-through-triz-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/03/a-simple-problem-but-not-able-to-think-through-triz-principles/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple problem where Load Capacity of a vertical bar needs to be increased without increasing Lateral areas and Material. There is one proposed solution as shown below. I would like to check two things with you
 Is the solution proposed really resolves the contradiction? (Load Capacity Vs Crossectional Area)
 If yes, Which TRIZ principle helps to think of solution like this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new arsenal to fight old enemies</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/03/a-new-arsenal-to-fight-old-enemies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 16:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/03/a-new-arsenal-to-fight-old-enemies/</guid>
      <description>A new arsenal to fight old enemies by Martin recently in The Hindu is one of the extreme examples of Resources (something that is available for free and has potential utility) that I have seen. I am reproducing the article below with emphasis on Resources, check it out. The frequency of resource occurring in our mind is possibly higher only if we pay attention deliberately.  {.detail-title}   A farmer in Nilampur puts to good use FM radio broadcasts against wild boar raids on her yam and tapioca farm    What do detergent cakes, abandoned compact discs, sardines, FM radio broadcasts and good old garlic have in common?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Level Engineering: Thanks to TRIZ India</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/next-level-engineering-thanks-to-triz-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/next-level-engineering-thanks-to-triz-india/</guid>
      <description>What Engineers must need to know today ?     Reiterating the words from Management Guru Peter Ducker     &amp;#8221; Teach them what they don’t know today if you want to achieve phenomenal success tomorrow&amp;#8221;     With reference to image below and with respect to my observation, engineers today are doing brilliant job at providing engineering solutions and optimization studies. But there is hardly any drive for Innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical TRIZ Workshop Resources Workbook &#43; Presentation &#43; Reference</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/practical-triz-workshop-resources-workbook-presentation-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 06:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/practical-triz-workshop-resources-workbook-presentation-reference/</guid>
      <description>We had given out a TRIZ India Workbook with enough space to doodle, brainstorm and use the specific guidelines on techniques used. While the appendix with the Business and Management Contradiction Matrix can be referred on Darrell Mann reference, available on amazon
We had also used TRIZ India Workshop Presentation , typical structure that we had for techniques is as follows
 the basic theory or other basis behind the technique a strong story where it was applied from either a personal experience or from other sources personal/individual application group application and facilitation notes  While we saw tremendous enthusiasm from industry (across IT, Oil and Gas, Energy, Pharma, Engineering in this workshop alone) we hope to get broader participation from academia as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Intellect Evolution</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/human-intellect-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/human-intellect-evolution/</guid>
      <description>We are seeing ever increasing complexity in today’s life. What comes to help are the principles and theories which combines millions observation into single discipline It’s like this if I know law of gravity then I don’t have to study and monitor curvilinear path for every projectile motion on the earth. I can simply draw it using laws of motion.
TRIZ principles are serving the same purpose where we don’t need to reinvent the wheel everytime we need innovations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whether the concepts and philosophy of TRIZ is applicable to other than technical systems? Here is an article on TRIZ and society..- how to win enemies without Fighting?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/whether-the-concepts-and-philosophy-of-triz-is-applicable-to-other-than-technical-systems-here-is-an-article-on-triz-and-society-how-to-win-enemies-without-fighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 06:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/whether-the-concepts-and-philosophy-of-triz-is-applicable-to-other-than-technical-systems-here-is-an-article-on-triz-and-society-how-to-win-enemies-without-fighting/</guid>
      <description>The contradiction We don’t want to set up a fight but we want to see our enemy is punished. We don’t want to kill our enemy by ourselves or by deploying others but we want to see that the enemy is dead. We don’t want to follow any method of violence but we want to see all our enemies dying before us.. Is it possible to break the above contradiction? .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we apply TRIZ for personal and spiritual attainment, please read another interesting article “TRIZ and Spirituality: The methods of Maximizing Happiness”</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/can-we-apply-triz-for-personal-and-spiritual-attainment-please-read-another-interesting-article-triz-and-spirituality-the-methods-of-maximizing-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 06:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/02/can-we-apply-triz-for-personal-and-spiritual-attainment-please-read-another-interesting-article-triz-and-spirituality-the-methods-of-maximizing-happiness/</guid>
      <description>TRIZ is a method of high level of commonsense and can be applied in any field, whether social, economical, technical or spiritual. This article analyzes the concept of happiness, the ultimate goal of human being, and demonstrates the application of different TRIZ concepts like Ideality, contradictions, Principles, Resources and Trends in different theories of maximizing happiness. please read the aticle at http://www.triz-forum.tk/blog/view/48/triz-and-spirituality-the-methods-of-maximizing-happiness and post your comments..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZIndia at Kolkata</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/01/trizindia-at-kolkata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 06:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/01/trizindia-at-kolkata/</guid>
      <description>I represented TRIZIndia in the recent conference on Invention, Innovation &amp;amp; Technology held at Kolkata 19-21 Jan. The conference was dedicated to Acharya Prafulla Chandra Ray (P.C. Ray) who was a great Chemist Innovator and Entrepreneur &amp;#8211; he started the Bengal chemical industry (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prafulla_Chandra_Ray)
 I came across a bunch of very dedicated scientists who are passionate about TRIZ.. The conference efforts were lead by Dr Mukherji, Dr Ambar Ghose and Dr Shubrato Ghosh of IAPQR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website runs without internet..Trim the most important function or resource</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2012/01/website-runs-without-internet-trim-the-most-important-function-or-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 05:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2012/01/website-runs-without-internet-trim-the-most-important-function-or-resource/</guid>
      <description>Re-post from http://trizit.blogspot.com 


Ok; this is for those who follow South Indian films and also know the &amp;#8220;super star&amp;#8221; in the Tamil movie industry, Rajinikanth. Do Google about him to know his super star power (in movies) and read some PJ&amp;#8217;s about him. But this is interesting, and not a joke, that his website www.allaboutrajni.com runs when there is no internet (a very simple solution technically)
 Read more about it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple rule of Innovating Technology</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/09/a-simple-rule-of-innovating-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 15:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/09/a-simple-rule-of-innovating-technology/</guid>
      <description>Inline with TRIZ Principle, we can devise a simple rule to understand and appreciate any product or technology we come across. I mentioned about the rule and it&amp;#8217;s application for Automotive technologies at the link below.
Hope you will like it
 http://smartfundas.blogspot.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Seperation Principle: Maximizing Trasport Service Revenue and Passenger Convenience</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/09/triz-seperation-principle-maximizing-trasport-service-revenue-and-passenger-convenience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/09/triz-seperation-principle-maximizing-trasport-service-revenue-and-passenger-convenience/</guid>
      <description>**
**
Being in Pune I am just taking the case of local public bus transport however I am sure this applies to any general transport meant for public. The public road transport service (PMPML) in Pune although wide spread across the city is not the certainly the most profitable with it&amp;#8217;s fixed frequency schedule and a assumption that affordability of this transport is same for all commuters from all sections and classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What would a Bumble Bee do ?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/09/what-would-a-bumble-bee-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 16:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/09/what-would-a-bumble-bee-do/</guid>
      <description>Look at your Problem through different lenses
The first step to come up with innovative ideas is to look at a problem innovatively i.e look at the problem through different lenses. We tend to look at a problem from only one angle &amp;#8211; but how to trigger our mind to look at it from different angles ? Try asking the question what would X do &amp;#8211; X could be Steve Jobs or Buddha or Don Quixote or Gandhi or your own Grandfather or Mother-in-law &amp;#8211; the idea is to bring a new perspective to the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ India podcast #3 – 9-Windows</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/08/triz-india-podcast-3-9-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 01:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/08/triz-india-podcast-3-9-windows/</guid>
      <description>Bala Ramadurai, Murali Loganathan, Prakasan Kappoth and Shankar Venugopal discuss &amp;#8220;thinking out of the box&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;big picture thinking&amp;#8221; citing examples of BMW, software development, dispensing cash on the third podcast of the series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ India podcast</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/07/triz-india-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 06:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/07/triz-india-podcast/</guid>
      <description>The inside story of TRIZ India podcast was published by Ellen Domb in her commentary.  &amp;#8220;Podcast was one of those ideas which came to me when I was stuck in Bangalore traffic and I thought this is the best resource to listen to podcasts. So, I listened to Getting Things Done podcasts streaming from my cellphone to the car stereo. One fine day, it hit me that TRIZ should have a podcast of our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulate the Future</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/05/simulate-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/05/simulate-the-future/</guid>
      <description>What makes you most uncomfortable taking the decision?&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;.
&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;..And the simplest answer could be &amp;#8220;No clear idea of future outcome and events&amp;#8221;. Although probability helps us to provide possibilities in future it doesn&amp;#8217;t tell in any way the exact future outcome. If the coin is tossed, there is equal probabilty for head and tale however can someone tell the exact outcome. And that&amp;#8217;s where the whole uncertainity is. I believe the most successful people have ability to guess future closer to it&amp;#8217;s exact outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making : You need the tool!</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/05/decision-making-you-need-the-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/05/decision-making-you-need-the-tool/</guid>
      <description>PRINCIPLE: The best decision ensures Highest Ideality Future Outcome for situation under consideration. Note: The ideality for the short term and long term future may be different and needs judging on what is desired.

 TOOL : TRIZ and Innovation methodology can be very powerful for decision making in every aspects we deal in personal and professional life. I am just highlighting the simplest decision tree especially when options are available to choose and start with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Developers Summit-2011</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/02/triz-developers-summit-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/02/triz-developers-summit-2011/</guid>
      <description>http://www.triz-summit.ru/en/section.php?docId=4908
Information Letter 1   Information letter #1, November 30, 2010.     TRIZ Summit 2011      Dear colleagues!   1. The Organizing Committee of TRIZ Developers Summit selected the topic for Summit-2011 &amp;#8211; it is &amp;#8220;Action Principle of Systems&amp;#8221;. This topic is very important for TRIZ research. It embraces issues of system modeling, functional analysis and synthesis, trends of engineering systems evolution and methods for forecasting via transfer of functions and trends of such systems, and terminology issues in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: TrizIn 2011 – 2nd Annual TRIZ India Summit</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/01/call-for-papers-trizin-2011-2nd-annual-triz-india-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 19:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/01/call-for-papers-trizin-2011-2nd-annual-triz-india-summit/</guid>
      <description>This is a Call for Papers to be presented at the 2nd Annual TRIZ India Summit, taking place on July 28 &amp;amp; 29, 2011 at Bangalore. The summit is being organized by Crafitti Consulting in partnership with The Altshuller Institute for TRIZ Studies (AITRIZ).
http://2011.trizindiasummit.com
 Summit Topics  TRIZ Papers  Our emphasis is on REAL case studies of TRIZ being applied in problem solving and innovation contexts. We are strongly interested in providing content for corporate and academic use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you shouldn’t eat (use) an Apple?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2011/01/why-you-shouldnt-eat-use-an-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 12:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2011/01/why-you-shouldnt-eat-use-an-apple/</guid>
      <description>If you are an Apple fan from India, this is for you, and I wouldn’t mind you shout at me. I used to be a great Apple fan. I used the Mac system in 2002 time period and ever since in love with their products, company for their innovations, and later Steve Jobs as a spatial thinker (also because I’m a spatial thinker) after reading his biography. Then the news came, Apple coming out with a phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shesh, Adi &amp; Anatha Three Stages of Customer Intimacy</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/12/shesh-adi-anatha-three-stages-of-customer-intimacy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/12/shesh-adi-anatha-three-stages-of-customer-intimacy-2/</guid>
      <description>Visit My Blog
 http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shesh, Adi &amp; Anatha Three Stages of Customer Intimacy</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/12/shesh-adi-anatha-three-stages-of-customer-intimacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/12/shesh-adi-anatha-three-stages-of-customer-intimacy/</guid>
      <description>Visit My Blog
 http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Book on TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/free-book-on-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 17:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/free-book-on-triz/</guid>
      <description>Also a free PDF of my latest book &amp;#8220;Da Vinci and the 40 Answers&amp;#8221; can be found on my web site if anyone wants to download it
www.slyasafox.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Da Vinci and the 40 Answers Videos</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/da-vinci-and-the-40-answers-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 17:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/da-vinci-and-the-40-answers-videos/</guid>
      <description>Prakasan,
Thanks for posting some of my videos&amp;#8230;.here are those 4 and some more
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxDDFnT5qTQ http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ToMvi02AIlI&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RNaDxz1ARTM&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xDkoW9UrH5k&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2oWfy1-z-So&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fs1_xVUDmzQ&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s4b0akKQJ-U&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Aik9PnvrjPY&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m6JxuaQUbEM&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7gNBM6OWqNQ&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLbXOijqRjA&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fF-L350xzFc&amp;feature=related http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fF-L350xzFc&amp;feature=related </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ India Summit 2010 proceedings are now online!</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/triz-india-summit-2010-proceedings-are-now-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2010 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/triz-india-summit-2010-proceedings-are-now-online/</guid>
      <description>Crafitti is pleased to announce that TRIZ India Summit 2010 proceedings are now public and online! You can access the proceedings at https://sites.google.com/a/crafitti.com/triz-india-summit-2010/. Please feel free to share the link with your network.      In lieu of our strategic partnership with Altshuller Institute for TRIZ Studies, TRIZ India Summit 2010 papers are also part of TRIZCON 2010 proceedings! You can access TRIZCON 2010 proceedings at http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling the Innovation Summit – Surviving the Avalanches and Avoidng the Yetis – Growing Ideas into Innovation</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/scaling-the-innovation-summit-surviving-the-avalanches-and-avoidng-the-yetis-growing-ideas-into-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 13:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/11/scaling-the-innovation-summit-surviving-the-avalanches-and-avoidng-the-yetis-growing-ideas-into-innovation/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to address the CII Karnataka Innovation Forum last week. I spoke about the Challenges in growing ideas into innovation. I outlined the Innovation FlowTM Framework and gave a quick intro to TRIZ-based Innovative Problem Solving. There was good interest from the Innovation forum to learn more about TRIZ.. I plan to do a one-day innovation workout for them next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Party is over for Google? A TRIZ Analsysis</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/search-party-is-over-for-google-a-triz-analsysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 19:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/search-party-is-over-for-google-a-triz-analsysis/</guid>
      <description>Cross posting from TRIZ Journal Commentary
   I posted a commentary on search engine and IFR of a search engine here a while back; as search engine has found a place in my TRIZ examples, I thought of giving a shot to this news article (Google: The party is over) appeared in Fortune recently through another TRIZ interpretation. While I wouldn&amp;#8217;t state that Google is struggling to find the next innovation, statement like slowing down their core business of search is certainly intriguing me especially when some data points are given by the authors from their research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNIVERSAL PROBLEM HAVE TO BE SOLVED INVENTIVLY</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/universal-problem-have-to-be-solved-inventivly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/universal-problem-have-to-be-solved-inventivly/</guid>
      <description>Dear members
This is my first contribution ,I have a problem and I hope all members share me for generating solutions using triz tools.
The problem is &amp;#8221; Olders get double fracture due to Sudden fall&amp;#8221;
Older need to move freely and at the time of fall ,he/she should be protected from any Fracture or pain
wating for your ideas &amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230;
NOTE : I posted this problem in TRIZ for problem solving group and I post the problem here as per mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two TRIZ India Summit 2010 Papers featured on AITRIZ this month!</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/two-triz-india-summit-2010-papers-featured-on-aitriz-this-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/two-triz-india-summit-2010-papers-featured-on-aitriz-this-month/</guid>
      <description>Two TRIZ India Summit 2010 papers are featured on this month&amp;#8217;s AITRIZ edition of Inside TRIZ, as a follow-up of Crafitti&amp;#8217;s strategic partnership with AI for TRIZ India Summit.
       Enhancing Air Safety for Pilots and ATC using TRIZ, A.K.Dhamija, K. Ramachandran, Divya Gautam, DRDO http://www.aitriz.org/articles/InsideTRIZ/323031303039695452495A.pdf   Determining Qualitative Parameters Using TRIZ for Estimating IP Value of Intangibles, Pinaki Ghosh, Subhadip Sarkar, Prasanna C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Design: For those who believe beyond Obvious!</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/product-design-for-those-who-believe-beyond-obvious/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/product-design-for-those-who-believe-beyond-obvious/</guid>
      <description>Product : A new perspective
   Lets me start with the question before going on to principles (not techniques) of product design
 What is meant by the successful product?
 I talked to few people around and recieved the following consistent answers..
1.A successful product is what organizes produces to earn profits
2. A successful product is what customers wants and are ready to buy
3.A successful product is what is designed with right tools and processes, with all operational aspects, voices of customers and potential failure modes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Furniture – Solving Physical Contradictions?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/resource-furniture-solving-physical-contradictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 03:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/resource-furniture-solving-physical-contradictions/</guid>
      <description>The concept isn&amp;#8217;t new. The IKEA of world has done it a while back, and the classic TRIZ examples dated in 1960 has examples of same from Japan. But, this video is an interesting one, shows different options, and apart from all, the beauty associated with it, and for us, good examples of TRIZ techniques.     Physical Contradictions are considered as closest point of a completely new invention according to TRIZ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IFR at Google</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/ifr-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 08:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/09/ifr-at-google/</guid>
      <description>Thought I will share this snippet about IFR from Google.   Isak Bukhman while he was in Bangalore for the TRIZIN conference, declared that IFR has nothing Ideal or Final about it and I would add, it is possibly not a result of something as well.    Google operates this website called http://www.dataliberation.org/
 &amp;#8220;with the singular goal to make it easier for users to move their data in and out of Google products&amp;#8220;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On time and relationships</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/08/on-time-and-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 09:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/08/on-time-and-relationships/</guid>
      <description>No, I did not intend to start an alternate career in family counselling with this post. This post is on representation of time and relationships in SI. I have always had this difficulty, that both do not seem to fit in within any single tool.     Take for instance 9-Windows, while it is great to have your system in the middle and actually be able to see how it evolves over time (the X Axis) and look at all that happens around and inside, it is way too unclear when you want to represent any relationship between your present system with an element in the super-system future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding DNA of Great Minds</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/08/decoding-dna-of-great-minds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 15:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/08/decoding-dna-of-great-minds/</guid>
      <description>Mathematics to most of us is a subject to be hated and loved at the same time. On one hand, the enmity with mathematics is because we had to learn, memories a pattern / method taught to solve a problem in anticipation of the problems we might face in our real life when we are out in the world from our safe cocoons. Although I never applied math to my real life problems as they seem to be more complex to solve with the scant knowledge of mathematics I possess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>trenDNA – Understanding Populations Better Than They Understand Themselves</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/08/trendna-understanding-populations-better-than-they-understand-themselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 04:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/08/trendna-understanding-populations-better-than-they-understand-themselves/</guid>
      <description>trenDNA_051067.doc
It’s some time now that I haven&amp;#8217;t come up with something new for your grey matter. I mentioned to you about reading a book titled “trenDNA” ( Understanding Populations Better Than They Understand Themselves) &amp;#8211; a book by Darrell Mann and Yekta Ozozer. I finished reading it and now deeply diving down to explore the approach and hunt for the innovation challenge treasure .Here I am with a brief summary of trenDNA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ – Merging Example</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/07/triz-merging-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/07/triz-merging-example/</guid>
      <description>Check out TabCandy (Watch the video).
 http://www.azarask.in/blog/post/tabcandy/  Aza Raskin (Author of TabCandy &amp;#8211; His dad started the Macintosh project for Apple)
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aza_Raskin  This is one of classic example of TRIZ &amp;#8211; Merging principle in actions  Surprising why it took such a long time to come up with such a basic idea  I guess that in general innovation/innovators come up with crude, complex, not-ready mashed up versions of ideas Then it is eventually refined leading to incremental innovations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altshuller, Science Fiction and TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/altshuller-science-fiction-and-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 05:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/altshuller-science-fiction-and-triz/</guid>
      <description>Altshuller not only classified inventions (based on study of patents), he also classified science fiction concepts, although in a slightly different manner! Not a surpise at all, after all inventions are science fiction till they become reality!

 In order to study the mechanism of SF, it was necessary first of all to collect ideas scattered in thousands of works, to classify them, and then compile A Register of SF Ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthing Organisational Innovation Capabilities – Life Stages of a Butterfly</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/birthing-organisational-innovation-capabilities-life-stages-of-a-butterfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 11:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/birthing-organisational-innovation-capabilities-life-stages-of-a-butterfly/</guid>
      <description>http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com/2010/05/birthing-organizational-innovation.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Systematic Innovation Guru Darrell Mann &amp; Thoughts of Rejuvenation</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/meeting-systematic-innovation-guru-darrell-mann-thoughts-of-rejuvenation-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/meeting-systematic-innovation-guru-darrell-mann-thoughts-of-rejuvenation-2/</guid>
      <description>http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com/2010/05/meeting-systematic-innovation-guru.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Systematic Innovation Guru Darrell Mann &amp; Thoughts of Rejuvenation</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/meeting-systematic-innovation-guru-darrell-mann-thoughts-of-rejuvenation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/06/meeting-systematic-innovation-guru-darrell-mann-thoughts-of-rejuvenation/</guid>
      <description>http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com/2010/05/meeting-systematic-innovation-guru.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation Internship using TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/04/innovation-internship-using-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 14:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/04/innovation-internship-using-triz/</guid>
      <description>Dear All,      I am now pursuing ‘Advanced Master in Innovative Design’ (AMID), at INSA-Strasbourg, France. Whole program thrust is totally on Invention Creation and Innovation Management in Company using TRIZ &amp; OTSM. The following is broad description of program. The course is delivered by 12 outstanding TRIZ &amp; OTSM experts. It has 413 hours formal Instruction. Prior to this I had excellent introduction on TRIZ in India by several TRIZ experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Article in the TRIZ Journal : ” TRIZ &amp; Fuel Saving Winglets”</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/04/my-article-in-the-triz-journal-triz-fuel-saving-winglets-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 17:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/04/my-article-in-the-triz-journal-triz-fuel-saving-winglets-2/</guid>
      <description>My article &amp;#8221; TRIZ &amp;amp; Fuel Saving Winglets&amp;#8221; is published in this month&amp;#8217;s issue of The TRIZ journal.
I talked about &amp;#8220;Building Innovation Capability ; Process of Reverse Ideation&amp;#8221; in my last blog post which incidently was my 100th blog post, wherein I said, see a solution addreesing a problem &amp;amp; then go back and find out what, why, when, where, how of the problem to learn more about it. I found this as the best way to improve my own innovation quotient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Article in the TRIZ Journal : ” TRIZ &amp; Fuel Saving Winglets”</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/04/my-article-in-the-triz-journal-triz-fuel-saving-winglets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 17:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/04/my-article-in-the-triz-journal-triz-fuel-saving-winglets/</guid>
      <description>My article &amp;#8221; TRIZ &amp;amp; Fuel Saving Winglets&amp;#8221; is published in this month&amp;#8217;s issue of The TRIZ journal.
I talked about &amp;#8220;Building Innovation Capability ; Process of Reverse Ideation&amp;#8221; in my last blog post which incidently was my 100th blog post, wherein I said, see a solution addreesing a problem &amp;amp; then go back and find out what, why, when, where, how of the problem to learn more about it. I found this as the best way to improve my own innovation quotient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Brain theory</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/03/split-brain-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 04:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/03/split-brain-theory/</guid>
      <description>For the naysayers, here is the link that illustrates the split brain theory. This theory won Roger Sperry a Nobel Prize. such is the power of the split brain theory.
What is the split brain theory ?
There are 2 distinct functions in the brain &amp;#8211; logical and creative. Roger Sperry&amp;#8217;s experiments prove that logical (or commonly left hemisphere of the brain. For south paws, it is interchanged) thinking is associated with verbal, analytical, linguistic abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Building Innovation Capability – Process of Reverse Ideation:”</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/03/building-innovation-capability-process-of-reverse-ideation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 04:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/03/building-innovation-capability-process-of-reverse-ideation/</guid>
      <description>It gives me a pleasure to share 100th blog post of your blog “Innovation Nukkad” The post is about “Building Innovation Capability – Process of Reverse Ideation:”
Following week I am going to share a case study I put up using the approached ilustrated here, so this post is for making a ground for you to appreciate the case study.
Visit : http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com for the post.
Stay Connected.
Love &amp;amp; Warm Regards,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Weight Vs Heavy Weight</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/02/light-weight-vs-heavy-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 17:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/02/light-weight-vs-heavy-weight/</guid>
      <description>decided to be fit this year and reduce my personal carbon footprint by introducing a bicycle in my daily life. I spent more money (considering this will be a worthy, onetime investment) than I would spend in a high class fitness center on this. This one is an imported bicycle, weighing about 5 -8 Kg (I heard there are cycles weigh just about 5 Kg!), and attracts lot of attention when I ride 🙂 As we all know, the reduced weight is an important aspect of racer bikes to provide enough comfort, speed, modularity etc to the rider, but the reduced weight is also a big problem in India for the high end cycle consumer base, and may be in many other countries too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ in Engineering colleges in India</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/02/triz-in-engineering-colleges-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 03:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/02/triz-in-engineering-colleges-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Hi
This forum should try to introduce TRIZ in engineering college curriculam. TRIZ is being taght in Russia even in schools. We should be able to introduce it in Engineering graduation courses.
Joseph</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Future Air Travel and Principle 16</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/01/our-future-air-travel-and-principle-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 16:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/01/our-future-air-travel-and-principle-16/</guid>
      <description>Airline business makes its revenue and in turn profit per seat per mile flown. Naturally it is in their best interest to put more seats in the aircraft and the airline manufacturers have to oblige to see that its customers remain profitable. From 31 inch it may be reduced in future to 25 inch to accommodate more passengers. I recollect Principle 16 Partial or Excessive Action which reads “ If exactly the right amount of action is hard to achieve , use “ slightly less” or “slightly more” of the action, to reduce or eliminate the problem”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design for Tranquility</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/01/design-for-tranquility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 16:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/01/design-for-tranquility/</guid>
      <description>Mumbai suburban trains are like Bhel Pots. They accommodate different ingredients of human personas making travelling as delicious as Mumbai Bhel. Some of the ingredients of this moving Bhel Pot are gamblers, readers, dozers, chanters, chatters, amateur singers &amp;amp; the grumblers (you can add your own to make it tastier).
There are many types of grumblers who spice up this Bhel; one of them is the one who is victim of the falling luggage (“Luggage Slide” similar to a “Landside”).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experiments with New Year Gadgets</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2010/01/my-experiments-with-new-year-gadgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 04:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2010/01/my-experiments-with-new-year-gadgets/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
Wishing you &amp;amp; your family a very Happy, Prosperous, Peaceful, Successful and Innovative 2010.
I have a new blog post : http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com
Lots of Love &amp;amp; Cheers for the Year
Prashant</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International IPR Conference @ Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/international-ipr-conference-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 03:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/international-ipr-conference-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>ITAG is organizing a conference on IP Leveraging in Software, Electronics and Green Technology in co-operation with Sughrue Mion PLLC, a leading law firm in USA and Bangalore Chamber of Industry and Commerce as our co organizer.. The conference will be held on 29th -30th January 2010 at Hotel LaLiT Ashok, Bangalore. The main objective of this conference is to create IP awareness in the field of Software, Electronics Industry and in Green Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Both Hand Drive, Malishkagiri &amp; TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 18:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz-2/</guid>
      <description>Some TRIZ Humour
http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Both Hand Drive, Malishkagiri &amp; TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 18:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/both-hand-drive-malishkagiri-triz/</guid>
      <description>Some TRIZ Humour
http://innovationnukkad.blogspot.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Clinic at MindTree</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/triz-clinic-at-mindtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 12:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/12/triz-clinic-at-mindtree/</guid>
      <description>Wow!! quite some time since I caught up with TRIZ India. Lot of things going on in MindTree on the TRIZ front. Murali (also a TRIZ India member) and I came up with the concept of TRIZ Clinic.
The Metaphor
Basically, we added the metaphor of a clinic to the problem definition and solution. Picture this &amp;#8211; a patient would go to a doc for a checkup when they have a fever or a cough or one such ailment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forkless Bicycle</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/forkless-bicycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 08:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/forkless-bicycle/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent invention by a designer. It is a bicycle without the front fork.
By removing the assumption that a front fork is necessary he forced himself to think of other ways to control the bicycle.[

&amp;#8221; target=&amp;#8221;_blank&amp;#8221;&amp;gt;]1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard Solutions</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/standard-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 20:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/standard-solutions/</guid>
      <description>Hi, We are trying to make an innovative design for a wheelchair and we have identified some physical contradictions. We are trying to find some references about the standard solutions of TRIZ . Anyone has an idea where to find them?
Thanks in advanced
Adrian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Book on Creativity and Innovation</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/free-book-on-creativity-and-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 13:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/free-book-on-creativity-and-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Free Book on Creativity and Innovation
My name is Mark L. Fox and I am author and leading authority on teaching practical creative thinking techniques for business. At age 31, I was the youngest person with the title of Chief Engineer on the Space Shuttle Program.
My latest book “Da Vinci and the 40 Answers”, A Playbook for Creativity and Fresh Ideas has been getting great reviews.
I just wanted to let you know that I have decided to provide the entire book for free in electronic (PDF) format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ-Sequential or Systematic?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/triz-sequential-or-systematic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/triz-sequential-or-systematic/</guid>
      <description>We had Shankar visiting us at Bangalore last month. One of the activities that we did while he was here was without getting into any technique-terminology of TRIZ is it possible for some one to use TRIZ?
We took one sample problem from the IT industry context about a web site experience. While we were doing this I was actively applying TRIZ techniques without deliberately naming it. As a note of thanks to Shankar I created a visual representation of what we did that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Mythology and TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/indian-mythology-and-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 09:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/indian-mythology-and-triz/</guid>
      <description>Stories feeds our pattern searching mind surely and so we all love stories as it feeds us with to find patterns.
One thing is sure about India (I am no longer dead sure about other things after knowing little bit of TRIZ as I remain most of the time in defining problem &amp;#8230; so rarely reach judgment part !!!), It has lots of stories and great ones. Ramayana, Mahabharata&amp;#8230; endless ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can this be Innovation?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/can-this-be-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 09:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/11/can-this-be-innovation/</guid>
      <description>I had recently been to a star hotel in Chennai
(Name not revealed as it a public blog)
This was where I was staying when attending a workshop
The hotel room was good but what triggered me the most was the shower
It took me close to 10-15 mins to know how to operate it
And operating it left water spraying from all different unexpected corners
How does one identify function of each of the ten knobs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design for Wow</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/design-for-wow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/design-for-wow/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever seen a new innovation, heard some music or looked at some art and uncontrollably said’ WoW’?
If so, then please click here: www.DesignForWow.
You may also like to see our survey of over 30 creative and problem solving techniques which may have helped develop the WoW
(Death by a Million Tools).
What ever you do, please rate our WoW examples AND add your own. We want to hear what you think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Hungry Appetite; Ideas for Hungry Mind</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/food-for-hungry-appetite-ideas-for-hungry-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 17:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/food-for-hungry-appetite-ideas-for-hungry-mind/</guid>
      <description>It is customary these days to eat out on a pre-diwali day with colleagues and this Diwali was no exception. This year we visited Delhi Durbar, a famous restaurant in Colaba, downtown Mumbai. The first impression of the restaurant was that of a cramped space (what can you expect in downtown Mumbai) but after inflowing inside I felt it was also roomy (Roomy, cramped are all relative terms so your opinion may differ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRAFITTI is Looking for Engineers and Scientists – Come and join us to create the Innovation based future</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/crafitti-is-looking-for-engineers-and-scientists-come-and-join-us-to-create-the-innovation-based-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 04:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/crafitti-is-looking-for-engineers-and-scientists-come-and-join-us-to-create-the-innovation-based-future/</guid>
      <description>Advertisement – Invention &amp;amp; Patent Analyst (Trainee)
Crafitti Consulting Pvt. Limited (http://www.crafitti.com) is looking for Invention &amp;amp; Patent Analyst Trainees with 0-2 years experience with following minimum qualification – BE/BTech (Chemical, Mechanical, Electrical, Computer Science, Bio-medical) or M.Sc (Chemistry, Electronics, biochemistry, etc).
Selected candidates will go through a comprehensive training course for one year as detailed below:
(a) 0-3 months: Training and Certification as Invention Analyst (No Stipend)
(b) 4-6 months: Application in live assignments (with stipend)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ – A Contradiction</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/triz-a-contradiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 04:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/triz-a-contradiction/</guid>
      <description>I was seeing through some of the slides that Shankar had so kindly shared and also the Videos that Prakasan had shared about Altshuller giving sessions on TRIZ
It set me thinking on one strange line of thought, that even TRIZ was A contradiction
The contradiction being that
We want Breakthrough innovations and making
it systematic and reachable and doable to everyone just makes the final
idea that is generated not &amp;#8220;WOW&amp;#8221; enough or thrilling enough</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t we innovate?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/why-dont-we-innovate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 09:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/why-dont-we-innovate/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;#8216;we&amp;#8217; in the question refers to the Indian IT industry.
I know there are people out there who would find this question offensive; but frankly that&amp;#8217;s not the intention.
We had someone coming over to present a Capability Maturity model for innovation at our office. It had a staged representation, similar to CMM, which organizations could adopt to become more innovative. True, lot of effort was put in to that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Altshuller – Father of TRIZ</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/remembering-altshuller-father-of-triz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 20:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/remembering-altshuller-father-of-triz/</guid>
      <description>I was introduced to TRIZ 4 years back, when I attended Darrell Mann’s course at IIT Mumbai. It was a great feeling at the conclusion of a two day course and I had a great satisfaction to have been introduced to something different which seems to have disrupted my learning curve. I was fortunate that I have been asked to further develop on it by my seniors at Mahindra and I started voraciously mining the literature on the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diwali Innovation</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/diwali-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 15:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/diwali-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Many times we come across unique artefacts, incidences, appreciate innovativeness of it at that very moment, but loose it like sea sand afterwards, not capturing its essence. Such incidences many times serve as “Innovation Boosters”, but they lay hidden deep in our pattern oriented brain and require external stimulus to bring it to the surface again. TRIZ provides a good external stimulus by way of analogy to excavate this hidden treasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem redefinition paper</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/problem-redefinition-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/problem-redefinition-paper/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone. We are a group of lecturers learning about TRIZ, we have stuck in a concept names &amp;#8220;Problem Redefinition&amp;#8221; from CREAX software. The reason to write in thie blog is to know if anyone knows about a paper or reference which might help us to clarify this concept?
Thanks in advanced
Adrian</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 second billing: Telecom Trends</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/1-second-billing-telecom-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 06:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/10/1-second-billing-telecom-trends/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday there was this announcement from TRAI (Telecom Regulatory Authority of India) that it may go on to make per second billing mandatory across all operators.
Currently this feature is a market differentiator, that only TATA DOCOMO offers such a billing of call on a per second basis.
Why do we need to watch this trend, because if all operators adopt this there will be a revenue reduction of 10% in the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ Solving Pet Problems</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/triz-solving-pet-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 17:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/triz-solving-pet-problems/</guid>
      <description>Those who own a pet, especially a dog will appreciate with what I am saying. It’s a demanding job to take your pet out for his routine every morning. He may be feeling relieved watering few electric poles but his “street” smart buddies do not take pleasure in his act &amp;amp; consider it an offense committed in their own terrain. They envy cozy life your pet enjoys and therefore start barking endlessly at him and indirectly at you; after all, you are the reason for his comfort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ and SIx Sigma live broadcast Sept. 30</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/triz-and-six-sigma-live-broadcast-sept-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 18:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/triz-and-six-sigma-live-broadcast-sept-30/</guid>
      <description>Event details. The timing is perfect for participation from TRIZIndia&amp;#8211;this is a live internet &amp;#8220;radio&amp;#8221; broadcast on TRIZ and Six Sigma (or any improvement method.) You can participate now, or listen/download later&amp;#8211;which is better learning AND more fun? Thanks in advance!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New (Free) Books</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/new-free-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 18:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/new-free-books/</guid>
      <description>I just got this announcement from Larry Ball about the latest from his consortium of authors:
_Just wanted to let you know that another book is available on http://www.opensourcetriz.comThe name of the book is “Job 4—Simplifying”. It regards tools for simplifying or overhauling a system. The download is also free. A for-pay trade paperback will be available in a couple of weeks._
My advice is that if you don&amp;#8217;t have &amp;#8220;Job 5&amp;#8211;Problem Solving&amp;#8221; you should get both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analogical Chemistry – Learning Can be Made Fun</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/analogical-chemistry-learning-can-be-made-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 12:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/analogical-chemistry-learning-can-be-made-fun/</guid>
      <description>Chemistry can be boring, if one’s chemistry with it is poor. The option then is to
accept without understanding what is written, memorize &amp;amp; score marks to have
better career prospects. . After all atomic theory was not invented by us.
We merely accepted it.
I was teaching my daughter a lesson in Chemistry and the topic was “Chemical
BONDS”. Since I left school, the only BOND I thought I knew was James Bond; I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ In Films – Ideas for Fooling “FILMI GHOST”</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/triz-in-films-ideas-for-fooling-filmi-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2009 15:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/triz-in-films-ideas-for-fooling-filmi-ghost/</guid>
      <description>Traveling 4 ½ hrs sitting on the last seat of a 25 seater bus, cramped &amp;amp; clamped is a nightmare. Some of you may empathize with me. My Mumbai- Nasik Return journey perfectly fits this case. In order to dampen this torture, smart transporters, like the one we have here, provide video facility &amp;amp; play latest hits. In TRIZ terms this is called innovation by transition to a super system (Video, films, latest hits etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5*(5Ws and 1H)</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/55ws-and-1h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 06:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/55ws-and-1h/</guid>
      <description>Before one gets into contradiction mapping, one needs to find out (5Ws and 1H)
 Who? Who was involved?
 What? What happened (what&amp;#8217;s the story)?
 When? When did it take place?
 Where? Where did it take place?
 Why? Why did it happen?
 How? How did it happen?
  Treating this like a mathematical equation
we have
Big picture=5W+1H
Toyota came up with the principle &amp;#8211; 5 Whys for problem definition and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battery Electrode climbs first rung of the Dynamization evolution ladder</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/battery-electrode-climbs-first-rung-of-the-dynamization-evolution-ladder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 07:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/battery-electrode-climbs-first-rung-of-the-dynamization-evolution-ladder/</guid>
      <description>As a materials scientist, I constantly look for breakthrough in new materials that enable technology to move up the evolutionary curve. I present here two recent materials innovation that enable cleaner batteries. The electrode of the battery is conventionally a rigid solid &amp;#8211; but this is no longer true.
(a) MIT invent ecofriendly 100%-liquid battery
http://www.greenoptimistic.com/2009/03/08/mit-liquid-battery/?wscr=1280&amp;amp;#215;800
What you see in the image is a liquid battery, everything in it is liquid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of a Book</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/evolution-of-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 17:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/09/evolution-of-a-book/</guid>
      <description>So, this must be something you have already seen in the news. ‘Digi-Novel’ Will Include Book, Video, Web
If there is one thing which has been around for centuries without much of an evolution is a book. While the process of manufacturing, papers, inks, machines etc would have gone through multiple S-curves, book is a book has been around as it is.
After reading this news, I was wondering if we are going to see a new S-curve in the evolution of a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday, Jacko!!!</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/happy-birthday-jacko/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2009 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/happy-birthday-jacko/</guid>
      <description>I pay tribute to my teen idol on his birthday and what I find that Jacko and I have something in common. He is an inventor dude as well!
Yes, Michael Jackson has a US patent issued to his name!!! Have you have seen his video &amp;#8220;Smooth Criminal&amp;#8221; or atleast this &amp;#8220;leaning&amp;#8221; position? This is his invention. What&amp;#8217;s interesting is the prior art in the patent. One of the prior art cited is from a space application where an astronaut in zero gravity conditions can benefit out of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Windows for a Project Manager and 6 Faithful Serving Men</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/12-windows-for-a-project-manager-and-6-faithful-serving-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/12-windows-for-a-project-manager-and-6-faithful-serving-men/</guid>
      <description>I was attending a workshop on Project Management (yes you heard it right). I wanted to brush up my PM knowledge after working as a “consultant” for few years, and also look at the new dimension of effective PM using systematic thinking methods, especially simple TRIZ tools. I set my expectation before attending this program that the Project Management Body of Knowledge would have embraced something different to say the PM BOK (Body of Knowledge) is evolving, and the session is going to teach me something new, such as using techniques for effective Project Planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Cloud 9 – the ideal cloud</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/on-cloud-9-the-ideal-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 03:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/on-cloud-9-the-ideal-cloud/</guid>
      <description>The trigger for this mini blog post is
http://www.capgemini.com/ctoblog/2009/06/the_ideality_of_the_cloud.php
Nice article on cloud computing. IFR for people stuck with an operating system (Linux or Windows) is no OS, but still we need the email, the apps and other functions.
So what is IFR for the cloud ? one that waters your plants, but doesnt exist.. 🙂 one that will rain, but not block light.
in the virtual world, one that lets me communicate with my friends/clients/customers without anyone else listening in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRIZ – key learning resources</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/triz-key-learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 07:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/triz-key-learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>Are you new to TRIZ &amp;#8211; are you wondering where to begin &amp;#8211; here are a few resources that you could look at:
TRIZ Books
Altshuller, Genrich (1973). Innovation Algorithm. Worcester, MA: Technical Innovation Center. ISBN 0-9640740-2-8.
Altshuller, Genrich (1984). Creativity as an Exact Science. New York, NY: Gordon &amp;amp; Breach. ISBN 0-677-21230-5.
Altshuller, Genrich (1994). And Suddenly the Inventor Appeared. translated by Lev Shulyak. Worcester, MA: Technical Innovation Center. ISBN 0-9640740-1-X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solution for the last mile problem – Successful innovation ideas</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/solution-for-the-last-mile-problem-successful-innovation-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/solution-for-the-last-mile-problem-successful-innovation-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The success and failure of innovation is overly discussed. Just do a google (or binging) around, and you will be directed to zillions of articles with advices and experiences listed out with &amp;#8220;n&amp;#8221; factors of success and failure of innovations. However, have you ever noticed the success of innovation some time is really dependent on solving the “last mile problem”?
Consider the innovations happening in the alternative fueled cars, especially Electric Vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic impact of increased US savings – Contradiction and opportunities?</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/economic-impact-of-increased-us-savings-contradiction-and-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/economic-impact-of-increased-us-savings-contradiction-and-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>An article published by McKinsey (March ’09) quarterly shows this interesting (to me at least) study on the increasing US consumer savings in the last couple of quarters. Well, in a time when we see the bad news all around, the tendency for the rest of us earning are naturally towards saving it for the rainy day ahead. Apparently this article also put some lights on the debt Vs income ratio and justifies the reason behind this savings trend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commitment versus Compliance: A TRIZ Contradiction</title>
      <link>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/commitment-versus-compliance-a-triz-contradiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 08:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trizindia.org/2009/08/commitment-versus-compliance-a-triz-contradiction/</guid>
      <description>Part 1
Case 1
Imagine this situation where you put together a bunch of mandates at various levels of management, till it reaches the last employee on knowledge capture or learning. May be you can just make a random metric based on contributions (you could complicate it by adding usage, pass through, linking, commenting, etc) to your organization’s knowledge base and give sufficient room to game for employees to have fun which anyway will happen!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>